It is 6:01 p.m. and I now call the uh
April 6, 2026 meeting of the city of
Cheyenne Planning Commission to order.
Staff, could you please call the role?
Bob Mati.
Lonnie Olsen here.
Amy Hernandez
>> present via Zoom.
>> Daryl Hibbons
>> here. Megan Connor
>> present remotely.
>> Tony Leard here. Boyd Wigum.
>> Mr. Chair, we do have corn.
Okay. Uh the first item is uh the
minutes for February 17, 2026 meeting.
If I can have a motion.
>> Chair, I would so move.
>> Second.
>> Any comments or corrections for those
minutes?
Okay. All in favor of approval, please
signify by saying I. I I
>> I
>> All oppose. Same sign.
Okay. Those meeting those minutes pass.
Now we do the minutes for March 2nd,
2026. Need a motion.
>> Uh chair, I would so move.
>> Second.
>> Any comments or questions,
corrections for those minutes?
All in favor, please signify by saying
I.
>> I I
>> I
oppose. Same sign.
So that passes. And the good news is our
real chair has just made an appearance.
So for the record, uh Boyd Wigum is now
in attendance and can take over. We just
finished the minutes.
>> Okay. Thank you, Commissioner Lair.
Uh, that brings us to
item A. Will staff please read it into
the record?
>> Item A, PUDC-26-34,
Sweetgrass PUD amendment.
>> Thank you. Do we have an agent for the
applicant?
Good evening, chairman, members of the
commission. Casey Palma, Palmer land
planning agent for the owner.
Um, so what you have before you tonight
is a a major amendment to the PUD. Um,
the reason it is major is because it
deals with the land use areas in the PUD
and adjustments to the land use
boundaries.
Um the PV park has not been developed by
the city. Um there's several reasons for
that since the inception of um of
Sweetgrass, but we've been working with
the city on uh establishing that park
and getting the parklands developed. And
part of that uh is the discussions with
the park department. The the dedicated
acreage of 72 more or less 72 acres uh
is is more parkland than the city wanted
to take on. So, uh, SweetGrass does not
want to reduce the total park in the
project, but, um, this amendment, uh,
changes the PD to allow for a 45 acre
public park, uh, to be placed at the
intersection of Murray and Loving Trail
where it was originally. Uh, and it
would also allow for the remainder of,
you know, 28 acres plus or minus to be
developed privately. So, uh, whether it
would be a private recreation center or
developed for for playgrounds or trails
or other uses, um, privately without
being citymained, this amendment also
does that. Uh, the only other amendment
that's proposed within this, um, is is
not really related to the park. Um, it
it would allow for kind of a a middle
ground amendment to the PUD. So,
currently there's a a minor adjustment
in the PED that would allow for sort of
staff um staff approval of of minimal
changes to the PED text and then a major
amendment like the one we're in tonight
that would allow for um land use changes
or or or major major adjustments to the
PED and and this uh amendment before you
denied also would allow for a zone
change process. So just like anywhere
else in the city in the city, if if a a
land owner or a developer wanted to
change an area of sweetgrass, say from
from low density to high density or from
uh commercial to residential or vice
versa, um the amendment in subsection H
would allow for, you know, kind of a
standard zone change process to change
from one land use within the PED to
another land use within the PD.
Uh, with that, I'd be happy to address
any questions you might have.
>> Thank you. Um, members of the
commission, questions for the applicant.
Um,
going once, going twice. Uh, Mr.
Pullman.
>> Yes,
>> Mr. Rim. Uh just before my time is
closed, I wanted to mention uh I I had
received a call today, had a great
conversation with a resident in the uh
PUD and I told him I would say that we
spoke. So I wanted to make sure that I I
got that off my chest before I stepped
down. Um so he he said generally his
major concern was just that the park
hasn't been developed. Um I also have
communicated with some folks on Facebook
in the neighborhood that have similar
concerns. So, I think everybody wants to
see the park developed and uh my
discussions with park and my my
understanding um is that moving forward
from this amendment and in conjunction
with a subdivision plat that we could
get forward on on at least some some
starting points for developing that
park. Um so, I told him I would I would
share that with you. He said he didn't
have any opposition to that and and he
hopes to attend the uh public service
committee meeting next Tuesday or
>> I two Tuesdays from now.
>> Mr. Dr. Palmer, I do have a couple three
questions. Did I hear you correctly? Uh
that that the owner of the P the
developer here would prefer to maintain
the full-size park. That would be the
owner's preference. Is that my Did I
understand that correctly or did I
misunderstand?
>> Um yeah, this is not specifically an
owner-driven change. Um, in our
discussions with the city, uh, community
park is generally 45 acres and that's
kind of how they budget and and how they
break things down. And so when we were
saying, which was based on the original
calculations when the PED was created,
uh, here's 72 acres that we're going to
give to the city, they said, well, hold
on. We only want 45 for a community
park. So, uh, should the 45 be developed
as a park and the remainder be
developed, um, there is a provision in
the code already to allow it to be
residential. There's still a balance of
approximately 30 acres um that is hoped
to be allocated by the developer at some
point in the future. Um we're looking at
different options for where that might
go, but um the city has said uh at least
for the time being that that their
maintenance and ownership provisions
should be limited to 45. Um since the
original code specified I think plus or
minus 60 acres and there is in fact 72
provi reserved. Um this amendment allows
for that to be
specifically dedicated to a 45acre park
in for now and then sort of leaves a
balance of 30 um to be developed
elsewhere potentially by the city but
not promised.
>> Okay. I I I wanted to follow up because
if I remember right, this this was
originally dedicated at the same time
the city was I believe we're voting on a
million dollars to buy land elsewhere
for similarly sized parks.
>> Okay, that's correct. Um, and my other
kind of my other question was is is as
we're looking at this, do I understand
correctly that there's even if the 45 is
is developed, there's if the city should
have a change of heart in terms of the
scope of the park, that's not off the
table with this unless the developer
goes ahead and develops this
for housing before then. Is that correct
or am I misunderstanding?
>> I'm sorry. Can you reset the question?
>> Am I correct or am I misunderstanding?
>> Um, at this time and with this
amendment, the intent is to plat exactly
45 acres, which the city has said is
their desired acreage, and then to
dedicate that land and then to work with
parks to get that land developed as
quickly as possible. Um, as you know, as
everybody in the room also knows, it's
uh it's been a long time coming. So, we
we'd hope to see more development in the
park. And there's several reasons for
that. Not all on the city. Um, but but
the intent is to um have the city and
the developer sort of fulfill that
promised agreement that there would be a
45 acre community park uh in this
location.
And then as I understood 30 acres,
wait and see.
>> 30 acres may be developed in the short
term for a a private recreational use,
which there I mean there there is a a
company in town locally owned that is
trying to find a spot to develop a
private recreational uh indoor
recreational facility. Um so they have
approached regress and um so they would
be able to develop on that 28 acres if
this amendment is approved. Um if they
don't develop it, it could still be
developed as a private park. Um it could
potentially be developed as residential.
Um, and even if it is developed uh for
some other use, there still is, you
know, some balance of public park that
may come in the future. But at this
time, the city doesn't have any interest
in additional parkland above and beyond
the 45 acres.
>> Okay, I think that answered my
questions. Any questions? Okay, thank
you.
>> Thank you.
>> Will staff please
present the report?
Chair, members of the commission, Connor
White, Planning Development Department.
Uh before you is the is a PUD amendment
for SweetGrass. Uh this is the full PUD
for SweetGrass itself. Um this map might
be a little hard to see, but on the
future land use map, the green portion
under the hatching, the red hatching on
the far west side, that is the park
location.
So this PUD amendment doesn't change the
location, doesn't change the future land
use map, doesn't change the zoning
within the PUD for that area. According
to the PUD, it is still labeled as uh
the community park.
With the proposed amendment, um it does
make changes uh as the applicant has
mentioned to the acreage that the city
would then uh be maintaining out of that
community park location. uh does love or
uh does reduce it down to 45 acres.
Um also as the applicant mentioned the
PD amendment does allow for subsequent
park dedication uh to fulfill the
remaining amount should the city want to
take on additional park land. Um at this
time city does not look to take any more
than the 45 acres.
Again, there's just updated language in
here about the dedication, um, how much
park area, who's maintaining it, who's
developing it.
And then this amendment goes into more
detail that would allow a portion of
that park area to be developed
privately.
Uh, would be with private recreational
uses as the applicant mentioned.
And then there was the added zone uh
zoning map amendment language um as
another route for the PUB amendment. Um
this is more restrictive than the UDC
as it does kind of condense it down to
needing to be a change up to 25%.
Anything over that 25% jumps it into the
major PUD amendment and would come back
as a larger PUD amendment. Otherwise,
anything that's at 25% or lower
basically just follows our zoning map
amendment uh regulations that are in the
UDC for notice process, anything that
comes forward. This doesn't change
anything out of the PUD. Um the PUD
specifically has in its own kind of zone
districts uh for different areas within
the PUD itself. So they have like their
own commercial zone or their own high
density, residential, low density,
medium density. So basically that's what
the zone change would be looking at
specifically is just the zone districts
within the PUD not actually amending any
area out of the PUD
staff did review this. Um our parks
department reviewed it. Parks and
greenway planner reviewed it. Um and
they didn't have any additional comments
or questions or anything like that when
it came to the PUD amendment. They do
support it. Uh, and with that staff does
recommend approval of the PUD amendment.
I guess I should also note I've had
several phone calls about the PUD
amendment. Um, I've just explained to
people that it it's not taking away the
park, just reduces what the city is
required to main or basically develop
and allows for private development of
the other portion. after kind of going
through and explaining to most people,
nobody seemed to really have any major
issues um with the amendment itself. So,
there was mostly just the concern as I
believe our applicant mentioned of
either the park disappearing or being
developed in some other fashion. Um but
once finding out that the park is still
going to be there um and will be built
at some point, I did get asked about
timeline.
Uh Mr. Palma had more information about
the timeline than I've had. Uh I didn't
realize that might be moving along a
little bit further uh with the park
sooner rather than later. Um but yeah,
with that again, staff does recommend
approval of this beauty amendment. I'm
available for any questions.
>> Thank you. Uh questions for staff from
the commission.
Okay,
I'll open this up for public comment.
Anybody please come forward and state
your name and address for the record.
>> Good evening.
My name is Tammy Shepard, 2100 Doran
Lane, Cheyenne, Wyoming.
And um I am in the Sweet Grass
neighborhood. And my question is if
they're taking away the land that is um
proposed for 72 acres for a park,
they're going to take away that 30 acres
because the city and parks do not want
to develop that land.
I don't believe that we should put in
high density in that extra 30 acres. And
that's my concern. I don't want to see
us surrounded with more apartments or
condominiums or town houses like we have
going up already and that's the backside
of the property which is a major
concern. So, I just wanted to find out
um when that 30 acres would be decided
upon, what they would do with it.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Anybody else from the public wish to
speak on the this item
in the room? Going once, going twice.
Is there anybody on Zoom from the public
that wishes to speak?
>> And I should mention for those on Zoom,
if you do have any comments, please go
ahead and use the raise hand feature.
>> Any indication of somebody on Zoom?
>> I do have one.
>> Okay.
>> Seth Medina, you should be able to
speak.
>> State your name and address for the
record. Yeah, my name is Seth Medina,
2228 Good Night Trail. Uh, my question
is more or less of a function of really
truly when development is actually going
to take place. Um, you know, we'd really
like to see some development take place
in that property, you know, in those
that the acreage, you know, to the to
the west there of the community itself.
So it' be more of a function of the time
frame you know for the development
itself to take place from the you know
45 acres the parcel that would actually
be handed over to the city itself you
know when when does the city actually
plan to you know more or less you know
break ground on on that land itself that
those would be the questions that I
would have don't expect you guys to have
answers now
>> thank you sir
And any other
folks on Zoom?
Anybody else in the room? Going once,
going twice.
Um, I'd like to call the agent up to
respond to questions as best as
possible. This will be the last
presentation
in public comment
>> before we close public comment. Uh Casey
Palma, Palmer land planning agent for
the owner.
>> Okay. Would you please address questions
that were presented as best as you're
able?
>> Um
>> if able.
>> Yes sir, Mr. Chair. Uh so in terms of
the timeline, I think I did speak a
little bit about that. Um Sweetgrass is
as anxious as anybody to see that park
develop. Uh there's there's several
hurdles uh in the way. I talked to some
audience members and told them earlier
uh the gas metering station in the
middle of Avenue C is one of them. So,
we are working to kind of put those
pieces in place to facilitate the city's
ability to develop that. I have had
conversations with parks and greenway
about moving that forward. I don't have
a specific timeline on that. Um but I uh
I think we we are all very hopeful that
we can move that forward very quickly. I
I anticipate that a plat will be coming
forward to this body
uh within the next three months or so um
that would at least establish those land
ownership boundaries um which would
include the the gas metering station
owned by Excel Energy. Um so I can't
give you any more detail to the timeline
of development um other than that. And
then as to Miss Shepard's concern, um,
and as staff noted, this leaves all of
that 72
to three acres in the recreational land
use zone. Um, the only allowed uses are
things that are allowed in the
recreational park zone. And so there
cannot be any any residential um
highdensity residential, town homes,
anything like that uh without going
through that zone change process that is
outlined in here. There's no intent to
submit a zone change for that. Just to
be clear, um it sort of came up in this
whole process as to you know what would
happen if somebody wanted to do uh ch
change a land use like that. Um but
everybody uh in the neighborhood would
get everybody required to be notified
would be notified um as was done with
this application.
Uh and
there was one other thing I thought that
had come up. Um oh I just wanted to
mention that that there is currently a
provision in the code that's not part of
this amendment that does say if that
parkland is not developed it could be
con converted to a medium density
residential use. Um, there's also no
intent to do that uh in the near future,
but that that provision is in there. So,
I don't want to mislead anybody. Um, but
there's no intention to develop it for
anything other than recreational uses.
>> Okay. Thank you. With that, uh, public
comment is closed.
uh commission.
I think we're looking for a motion
to initiate discussion if need be.
>> Mr. Chair, I move to recommend the
governing body approve the Sweet Grass
PUD amendment.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved by Commissioner Lar and
seconded by Commissioner Olsen.
Um, do we have any discussion
by commission?
Discussion. Okay. Amendments. Seeing
none, will the chair please call a roll?
Megan Connor.
>> I.
>> Amy Hernandez.
>> Hi.
>> Lonnie Olsen.
Tony Lair,
>> yes. Terrell Hibbons,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Chair, that motion passes.
>> Thank you. Will staff please read item B
into the record.
>> Item B, PLTA-26-1,
special use approvals, creation of the
regional entertainment overlay and
development standards for offtrack
bedding facilities. text amendment.
>> Chair, members of commission, Charles
Bloom, planning and development
director. Um, first of all, there is no
uh applicant presentation for this
because we are the city initiating this.
Um, I'm asking for another postponement
to the first meeting in May. Um, we have
made significant steps forward on this
um, amendment. We just had a couple of
other items that kind of popped out in
front of this that prevented it from
being finalized for this meeting. I'm
open for any questions that you may have
regarding this.
>> Thank you, uh, Director Bloom. And are
we looking for another one month
postponement?
>> Chair through you to the commission.
Yes, I'd be seeking a recommendation to
postpone this to the May 4th meeting.
>> Yeah. Thank you. Any questions from
other commissioners for staff?
Um,
do I need to open it to public comment?
>> I I guess
>> so. There's nothing really to discuss.
>> Oh, I think
>> I believe I'd like if there's anybody
here that was intending to speak to this
issue
that's in attendance from the public.
Public comments open once, going twice,
public comments closed.
Um,
looking for a motion.
>> Chair,
>> uh, Commissioner Olsson,
>> I move to postpone this item to the May
4th, 2026 planning commission meeting.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved by Commissioner Olsen
and seconded by Commissioner Hibben.
Uh discussion by staff of the motion.
Okay.
Will staff please call roll.
>> Lonnie Olsen.
>> I.
>> Amy Hernandez.
>> Megan Connor.
>> I.
>> Daryl Hibbons.
>> Yes.
>> Tony Lair.
>> I.
>> Mr. Chair. That motion passes.
>> Okay. Thank you. Staff, please read
them. Read item C into the record.
>> Item C, PUDC-26-32,
Bison Apartments Expedited Plat.
>> Okay. Do we have an applicant present?
Please come forward. State your state
your name. Welcome, sir.
>> Good evening. John Sers, agent for True
Grit Land Development. What you have
before you is uh the process of going
through what we came to several months
or almost a year ago for a conditional
use on an apartment complex that is uh
almost at CO at this point uh for a
certificate of occupancy. Um in the
request from the potential buyers, they
asked that we go ahead and we plat the
individual buildings. We have gone ahead
and brought that before you. Um, with
staff's recommendation, we have
succeeded and managed to comply with all
the necessary requirements and happy to
answer any questions should you have
any.
>> Okay, thank you.
Any questions for the applicant from the
commission?
Any questions from the commissioners
attending via Zoom?
Okay.
Thank you. I guess
will staff plead your please read your
report into the record.
>> Mr. Chair, commissioners, Morgan Dennis,
Planning and Development.
This is an expedited plat for 1.88 A8
acres
acres located north of West College
Drive
West Waltershide B Boulevard boulevard
and east of Grand Harmony Boulevard. The
site is currently finishing construction
for multiple forplex buildings. Um the
purpose for of this plot is to create
individual lots for the for the
buildings to be sold. Uh the common lot
will be sold as eight pieces alongside
the buildings. Each owner of the
buildings will be responsible for
maintaining the common lot and parcels
to the approved site plan.
The current land use map designates this
area as mixeduse commercial. The zoning
of this parcel is CB commercial
business. Multi-dwelling buildings are
conditional use in the CB zone. This
parcel received approval for
multi-dwelling buildings from the board
of adjustments in November of 2024.
uh CB zone. There are no lot minimums
for frontage or area. So, all the lots
proposed are buildable.
Um staff recommends approval of the
preliminary plat advancing the final
plat to the governing body.
Okay. Thank you. Any questions for
staff?
Any questions for staff from Zoom?
Commissioners on Zoom.
I think I've got a question.
Um,
as presented,
how is there any provision for
enforcement? And maybe this would be for
the for the applicant, but is there any
provision for enforcement
if what appears to be a common
uh parking lot is going to be sold off
as individually attached to the adjacent
buildings? In my understanding, that's
what's going to happen here.
and and maintenance. There's no HOA.
What are we going to do with tresp
passing complaints? Is the city
comfortable with that?
>> Uh Mr. Chair, through you to you. Um
so on the final plat there is a note
that says that assigns responsibility of
each eighth piece. Um some of this can
be better answered by the developer. Um
but yeah, there is a note on the plot
that assigns
a responsibility of maintaining the
approved site plan, whatever current
site plan that is.
>> Thank you. And I see an applicant that
looks like he's willing to come and talk
to me a little bit. Talk to us a little
bit.
>> Mr. Chair, through you John Sers's
agent. Um, in working through how this
open space and common space works,
tax-wise, somebody has to pay the bill.
So, what has been worked through with
city staff is that everybody has a 1/8
interest into the actual lot nine, which
is common open.
There will be a maintenance agreement
between all eight individual uniters so
that nothing can happen and be sold off
like detention ponds and various other
things that we've run into recently. So
with that said, there is an arrangement
for all that to tie in together.
Currently, it is under one family
ownership to be subdivided between
members of the family and it will stay
in that family trust that way. But that
was the way we had to go ahead and
prioritize which individual family
member received which individual
building with the idea that there is an
arrangement for lot 9 as they all have a
1/8 interest and nobody can solely buy
lot 9.
Okay, thank you. That's a little
different than what I heard from from
the initial presentation, but thank you
for the clarification.
Okay. Do we have any members of the
public here?
We've heard we've heard from the
applicant. We've heard from the city.
Any members of the public wish to speak
on this? Going once. Going twice. Public
comment is now closed.
Looking for a motion to discuss.
>> Chair,
>> Commissioner Olsson.
>> I move to approve the Bison Apartments
preliminary plat advancing the final
plat to the governing body.
>> Thank you.
>> Second. Have a second by Commissioner
Hibben.
>> Do we have any discussion
on the commission?
Mr. Chair,
>> Commissioner Lair.
>> So, I guess just thinking out loud, this
is this is a this is typical of a lot of
the subdivisions we have, right? We have
there's common property and or common
lots that are owned jointly by all the
individual owners of the
um normal lots. and they're jointly
responsible for the maintenance of those
lots. And then I guess in this case the
property taxes arrangements have have
been made to that they each have a 1/8
interest though that 1/8 is not
geographically defined. Is that is that
our understanding everybody?
>> Uh that was my understanding after the
followup from the applicant.
is that it was more of a 1/8 undivided
interest was my impression.
And Mr. Chair, just a just one more
clarification point because
I initially I I when I first looked at
this, I thought it was just the parking
lot that was commonly owned, but it's I
believe it's also a big band of land
around the outside of the individual
lots and up to the perimeter of the
property that maybe staff could m chair
through you. That is correct.
>> Okay. So it's parking lot plus basically
anything that the the lots the building
it's everything except for the lots the
buildings are on.
Any further discussion
comment from staff comment from the
commission?
Don't want to ignore commissioners that
are attending via Zoom.
Questions that need clarified?
Hearing? None. Will staff please call
role?
Errol Hibbons.
>> Hi.
>> Megan Connor.
>> Amy Hernandez.
>> I.
>> Tony Lair.
>> Lonnie Olsen.
>> I.
>> Mr. Chair, that motion passes.
Okay, thank you. Will staff please read
item D into the record?
>> Item D, Pudc-26-35,
Dry Creek Vista Final Plat.
>> Do we have an applicant or agent for an
applicant?
Good evening, chair, members of the
commission. Casey Palma, Palma land
planning agent for the owner. Uh what
you have before you tonight is a
subdivision plat to divide out two
existing residences from a larger
parcel. Um you may have seen something
about the vacation of the intervening
right ofway uh on this project. Uh,
essentially the vacation action and this
platting action are intended to clarify
and and clear up a long line of strange
title issues and and actions by the city
and county. Um, so the the current owner
owns both of those residences. The
intent here is to put each of them on
its own lot uh leaving a remainder lot
in the middle. There's sewer and water
in Rock Springs Court or Rock Springs
Street. And uh you know for for decades
the the driveway that currently falls in
in what used to be Frank Court is um
utilized as a private driveway. So this
plat just follows up on the heels of
that vacation action to create a land
division and and clarify the ownership
boundaries.
Be happy to address any questions you
might have.
>> Commissioners questions for the
applicant.
>> Mr. share through you.
>> I just wanted to make sure you're the
owner's comfortable with this uh
condition that staff is asking us to add
about the title commitment from the
title company or quiet title um
resolving or the east west Frank Court
that was vacated.
>> Yeah, thank you chairman through you. Um
I think the condition is somewhat
unavoidable. Um there's been a lot of
confusion regarding these rights of way
and the the the chain of title over
time. Uh the surveyor is currently
researching back in that title track and
talking to the title company about
verifying how how this ownership was
broken down. It was originally owned by
the county. Um Dry Creek was conveyed to
the city. Um, so there's a lot of issues
there, but I guess in short, um, we we
accept the condition as as kind of a
necessary part of this complicated piece
of land.
Maybe this is my J day job coming back
to haunt me. But
what happens if the applicant
does everything in their power to
accomplish
the condition and
doesn't happen, the court decides
otherwise or something like that.
Um, you're the attorney, not me.
So, um, I I think
We'll save that for staff, but I
wondered if that was an issue that had
come up.
>> Um, yeah, I think that generally, um,
all parties involved going all the way
back to to Larry County in 1987. Um,
everybody agrees that this is a fairly
acceptable representation of of what is
out there and how it should be
interpreted. um the reason for the
condition and I'll let SPA staff speak
more specifically to it, but uh is that
there's several different
interpretations of that center line of
Frank Court and and who owned what and
when. And so it just requires some some
deeper research. Um,
so
I don't think that I I mean I think I
can confidently say that my client would
be amendable to a postponement if you
thought that that was a better path
forward than putting the condition on
today. Uh there is no imminent
development action. This is merely a a
you know housekeeping issue in terms of
the the record. So,
uh, I think we do have some time between
now and the council approval to see
where, you know, whether an issue comes
up. Um, so for now, I I think it's
generally acceptable to recommend
approval of the plat as presented with
the condition. If the condition unears
something more complicated, the plat
would either not be able to be recorded
or would need to be held until, you
know, that issue was sorted out. So, um
I it's it's your prerogative how you'd
like to proceed.
>> Thank you. I just want to get some
feedback before you hear from the staff.
>> Sure. Any other questions for the
applicant?
>> Will staff please read your report into
the record.
Chair members of commission
counterweight planning and development
department. The plat before you is for
3.17 acres of land that is east of North
College Drive and north of Rock or yeah,
north of and adjacent to Rock Spring
Street.
Uh this is a final plat. Uh if you
remember, we did have we've had two
items of the same project come before
you. We've had the preliminary plat that
came first um that was submitted as an
expedited plat, but due to all of the
issues that were kind of coming up with
vacating Frank Court um the ownership
issues, we did basically change that to
a preliminary plat and only allow that
to come before US preliminary. Uh one of
the conditions on the preliminary plat
was that the applicant submit a vacation
map to the city and the city would
initiate the vacation.
uh that street vacation is currently on
third reading in front of council. Uh
was at public service committee today
does have a recommendation of approval
going into next Monday's council
meeting. Uh so I do believe that that
vacation will be approved and the street
will be vacated in its entirety.
Um so that condition that was placed on
the preliminary plat uh has been
fulfilled. Um
the one condition which is why there's I
guess I'll jump back a little bit. Uh
the property is on the future land use
map as urban residential. It is proposed
uh with three lots for residential. It
is zoned medium density res residential
within the city.
Um the northernmost lot does have a
residence and then that southeast lot
has a residence and then the larger lot
in the middle would be a vacant lot uh
for future development.
Going back to that condition that was
brought up, um, one of the outstanding
conditions that we had on the
preliminary plat that Seth or not Seth
staff felt wasn't um, fully fulfilled
was the clarification
and verifying the ownership um, of
basically the land that was vacated for
the east west portion of Frank Court.
um reviewing various plats trying to
figure out where that when it was
vacated, how it was vacated, who the
land was supposed to go to. There's
nothing that clearly defines that. Um so
that's why staff put that condition on
there that something be provided by
either a title company or the applicant
or the owner go through quiet title and
acquire uh the land in full in name uh
so that we know who that owner is. um
and have that for this plat
staff is not opposed to the plat uh
moving forward. That's why we have the
condition. That's why we didn't
recommend postponement or anything. We
would also like to see this area cleaned
up and get this taken care of. We just
want to make sure that everything is
taken care of to the point where we know
who owns the land, whose name is on it.
Making sure that's all clear and done
with because again, as even the
applicant mentioned, this whole area has
been very difficult to tell who's owned
what, when it was vacated, how it was
vacated,
and all of that. So,
um, but otherwise, uh, with the final
plant, we also did want necessary
easements to be provided. uh and then
making minor technical corrections.
A lot of those easements are being taken
care of with the vaca the vacation. So
there is an easement on stern well I
guess on this case for this plat the
western property line that does provide
access to the northernmost lot. Um there
is a bopu easement that is being
provided as well for the water and sewer
stub uh at the bottom of Frank Court
with the vacation as well. And then you
have your utility ements that are
provided with the plat. So
staff does believe that almost all of
the conditions placed on the preliminary
have been um
satisfied. Again, just noting that the
clarification and ownership uh staff
does not believe that has been fully
satisfied, which is why the condition
with staff's recommendation of approval
has been placed on this final plat.
And due to meeting all of the review
criteria with the condition as noted up
on the screen, staff does recommend
approval of this final plat. And I'm
available for any questions.
Any questions for staff from the
commission?
Any questions for staff from our
commissioners who are here via Zoom?
>> Mr. Chair, I have a question.
>> Yes, Commissioner.
>> So, I work so I work for a title
company, so I don't know if this is a
conflict of if if I need to recuse
myself from this. Um I I'm not sure what
title company they may be going through.
Um just wanted to throw that out there.
Commissioner Hernandez, do you have any
comments based on your knowledge in the
title industry that help help illuminate
this for the remainder of the
commission?
>> Um, I mean, I don't have any comment
right now. I was I wasn't really aware
of the project, so um I I'm not I
wouldn't be right now.
Okay. I don't I don't we don't lose a
quorum if if you choose to recuse
yourself.
Um would like your insight though. And
I've got a question for for staff on
this.
It was mentioned that the vacation of
the
road Frank Court is still pending before
city
um that it was before the public
services committee. Was there any
comment any discussion
that can be reported back that could
help us?
>> Uh Mr. Chair through you. Um fortunately
I missed the discussion because I was
stuck on the phone about our first item
that was on this agenda. Um, but I did
get an email from Director Bloom and was
also u made aware by uh Morgan that some
of the discussion that was had was just
about making sure that the residences
that are adjacent to the Frank Court
vacation can still access their
property. Um, the answer to that is yes.
Again, the property on this plat that's
all the way to the north has the
easement that runs along on this plat,
which would be the east side of Frank
Court, but the west side of the plat.
And the southwest
property that's at the intersection of
Frank Court and Rock Spring Street, they
will own half the street. So, it's
basically a driveway for them already.
It's now becoming their land and an
actual driveway for them. But my
understanding that's the only kind of
discussion that was had is just
questions about um
access for those properties that are
along Frank Court currently. Other than
that, there hasn't really been any major
discussions on the vacation itself. Um
and there is the recommendation of
approval for next Monday.
>> Okay. And kind of related to that, if we
recommend approval of this plat in its
current form
and for some reason the the vacation of
Frank Court fails on third reading,
does this can this plat proceed or are
we about a month ahead?
>> So, Mr.
>> Mr. Chair, through you. So, if this plat
was basically to be recommended for
approval and it goes to be introduced
next Monday, but next Monday the
vacation fails,
which I would like to state it highly
unlikely at this point with just how
council's been voting on it, but say it
does, um, then at that point staff would
have to recommend at council, we would
end up changing our recommendation and
recommending denial due to the failure
of the vacation because now this plat is
incorporating land that wasn't vacated
and they're trying to it would basically
you'd be vacating the street with this
plat which you're only vacating half the
street which the city wouldn't support.
So it would be fine if planning
commission still recommended approval
tonight. Um, and then if something
happened next Monday, staff would
basically just turn around and have to
be at council recommending denial
stating why uh due to the failure of the
vacation.
And then follow up to that as part of
the discussion, sorry to monopolize
discussion here. Um,
would there be an alternative and maybe
this would be better directed to
applicant. Would there be a better
alternative or some sort of an
alternative PL plat that could meet the
applicant's needs or would they would
they have to start all over
start the process all over from
you know application fee onward to try
to bring forward a plat that met their
needs if the vacation fails.
>> Mr. Chair, through you they could they
could either they most likely they could
postpone it. Um, and then they could
work on modifications that remove the
street vacation area. Um, again, there's
still the preliminary plat that is
approved. Um, so as long as a final plat
is similar to that preliminary plat,
that can still move forward. Um,
staff can usually find a way if
something like that came up. Again, I
think it's high at this point highly
unlikely that vacation is not going to
pass. Um, I guess there's always an op,
but I guess there's always a way that it
could just have six no votes, but I
think with the recommendation coming out
of public service committee with a
recommendation of approval, um, even
being a fully unanimously approved on
second reading, no discussion at council
on second reading, I should add as well,
I just don't foresee the vacation not
going uh, basically being approved and
moving forward.
Thank you.
Questions, comments from the commission,
>> Mr. Chair, through you. I just thinking
out loud, maybe we this is better
discussion when we're ready for a
motion, but I I have I feel like maybe
it would be more proper for the planning
commission's recommended recommendation
to the governing body to mention the
that that our recommendation is
contingent upon their vacation of Frank
Quarter, that approval of that item
that's already underway rather than us
just approving it as is and relying on
staff to
um hold it up in the governing body
later.
>> Is there a question for staff in there?
>> Uh I guess staff, what do you feel about
that? You you you're I guess that would
be the question. Yeah, because Connor
was the one that mentioned that uh the
staff would probably re change their
recommendation to the governing body to
not approve it if
eventually the Frank Court vacation
fails. So I I guess the question to you
is would it be more appropriate for the
planning commission to make that part of
the motion forwarding to uh to the
governing body?
>> Mr. shared through you to Commissioner
Leair
being you are the commission you you can
add that into your motion if you would
like if you believe that's something you
believe is uh should be in the motion
that it basically you recommend approval
of the final plat with SAP's recommended
recommended condition
um
I I'd have to think more about how to
word it but you could find a way to add
something in there um if you can think
of it of just noting that as long as the
vacation is approved. So, but again, the
vacation is going into third reading on
Monday. Um, so this plat won't even be
discussed until after the vacation would
technically be approved. So,
>> so I guess in short it is you can do it.
>> Any other questions from the commission?
I'll note now open this up for public
comment. Is there any are there any
members from the c uh public that are
here to speak to this? Public comment
going once, going twice. Public comment
is now closed.
Um
I don't think we've got any open
questions for the applicant.
I think I'm looking for a motion
and we can amend a motion as need be.
Looking for a motion on this. Mr. Chair,
I move to recommend the governing body
approve the Dry Creek Vista final plat
with staff recommended conditions.
>> Been moved. Do I have a second?
It's been seconded by Commissioner
Olsen.
Further discussion by staff. Comment by
I'm sorry, staff by the commission.
Anybody on Zoom?
Chair? I'm curious just uh regarding uh
what Commissioner Leard said if we want
to add that or not. I was trying to
brainstorm some language in my head and
I'm kind of having a hard time adding
like a contingent on the approval of the
vacation because it
it's a
Mr. Chair, let me ask the commission.
Would it would it be more helpful if I
just in my memo that I send to um
council add a statement in there that
this is planning commission's
recommendation as long as basically
Frank Court
um the vacation is approved. Is that
would that suffice for commission and
then I have it in the memo and then I
bring it up in my basically
presentation. Well, I don't know if I
need to bring it up at the presentation
if
if it's approved next Monday, but I can
bring it up that this was planning
commission's recommendation as long as
the vacation was approved. And if
vacation's approved, I
they do recommend approval,
commissioners.
the condition in there is is is the
commissioner's idea. I I have no
thoughts one way or the other. I I was I
guess as I thought about that before, I
was kind of thinking out loud and
wondering is that which is the more
appropriate way to go, but having
struggled again uh like Commissioner
Olsson with the difficulty of how to put
that in language because usually when we
talk about conditions, we're talking
about conditions to be opposed on the
applicant with the approval of the plat,
which is not the case here. Um, and I'm
completely confident that staff will
convey uh to the governing body that
this is tied to the vacation of Frank
Court. And as they say that that will
probably be a done deal
uh maybe just before this ever comes up
to council before they ever even discuss
it. So I
I I do not wish to attempt to amend it
myself even though I was the one that
brought it up.
commissioners
and I see the applicant and I believe
the applicant previously
indicated that postponement was not a
problem. I don't know if we need a
postponement, but
>> and
if the chair wants to I Charles does
have his hand raised, so let's see. Um,
chair through you. Um, director Bloom
does have his hand raised, so I'll let
him
uh maybe he's got something for the
commission on this
>> for the edification of the of the
commission. will recognize director blue
>> and chair. Members, chair through to
members of the commission. Um perhaps
language could be added to staff
recommendation as um item B which
follows A which could be the vacation of
rights of way within the plat boundaries
be approved
prior to city signatures on the plat
or prior to the city. Well, yeah, prior
to city signatures
um on the um being a fixed to the plat.
What that accomplishes
is that if the vacation action does not
occur, then the city planning director,
myself, and the mayor will not be able
to sign the approved plant.
that satisfy the commission.
>> I'm curious if this if this would be
acceptable to the applicant because
we're messing with the applicant's
project here.
Is there a desire to offer an amendment
conforming to Director Bloom's
suggestion or do we want to proceed as
is or something else?
>> Chair, I would move to amend it with uh
what Director Bloom referenced. I don't
have it word for word, but it would be
more or less adding a second condition
to the final to the final plat stating
that uh city signatures cannot be
affixed to it without the vacation of
Frank Court.
>> I'll take that as a motion. Is there a
second? Are there any thoughts from the
commission commissioners on Zoom?
And we
>> I see no second. I think the second
Sorry about that. Sorry about that, Mr.
Chair.
>> Okay. It's been moved and it's been
moved and seconded to to to amend the
amend the original motion to include a
second uh uh conditioning
applica uh a fix affixation of fixing
city signatures to the plat upon vaca
prior vacation of Frank Court.
>> Any discussion there? I just would want
to make sure that Commissioner Larard's
all right with that amendment to his
original motion. Just
>> and Mr. Chair, I am
>> okay. With that, any comment?
>> Mr. Chair, I would note that I do have
the exact language from Director Bloom.
So, I will make sure I have that as the
condition.
>> Okay. Any comment on Zoom?
Hearing? None. Will staff please call a
roll on the amendment to the motion?
All
right. Amy Hernandez.
>> Hi,
>> Tony Lair.
>> Megan Connor.
>> I
>> Daryl Hibbons.
>> Lonnie Olsson.
>> I.
>> Mr. Chair, the amendment
to the motion passes. So, we're back on
the main motion to approve
>> as amended.
>> As amended.
>> Okay. Is there any further discussion to
regarding the the main motion
to approve as amended?
Anything on Zoom?
Hearing? None. Will staff please call
roll.
Tony Lair. Hi.
Megan Connor.
I
>> Daryl Hibbons
>> I
>> Amy Hernandez
>> Lonnie Olson
>> I
>> Mr. Chair the motion to approve the
final plat passes.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Um
before we proceed,
do we want to
handle E F and G together or do we want
to handle these individually?
>> Uh Mr. Chair through you. So I think my
recommendation would be E be handled
separately as it's basically just the
assigned zoning but F and G do go
together and F and G actually have the
applicant on those but item E is just
staff as the applicant because it's the
assigned zoning portion of the
annexation.
>> Okay, thank you. Will staff please read
item E into the record?
Item E, PUDC-26-37,
Cox Land assigned zoning.
Will staff please read the report as
applicant.
Mr. Chair, members of the commission,
Conor Planning Development Department,
the item before you is an assigned
zoning. So, you've seen these quite a
bit. They all come with our annexations.
Um,
this piece of property is
uh out west of town. It is west of
Roundtop and adjacent to HappyJack Road.
This is an owner petitioned annexation.
Uh, the city does have land that we've
kind of hopped on and tied into the
annexation. It's for the city's water
treatment plant that's out there on
HappyJack,
but this is the land that is proposed to
be annexed. Um so it is everything that
is just in the shaded red area. So
with this assigned zoning um
this is for well there's the two
parcels. So you have the owner initiated
um owner petitioned which is the larger
parcel on the north side of happyjack
and then the city owned land that is on
the south side.
So, as always with the assigned zoning,
uh that is the only discussion that
we're having here tonight at planning
commission. We do not discuss the
annexation that happens at council. Um
this is just on the assigned zoning
aspect of this project.
through staff's review. Uh the larger um
parcel, which is either referred to as
the Cox Ranch Land Parcel or Cox Land
Parcel, uh that parcel uh that would be
proposed for the assigned zoning is
roughly 1,9
Wow, I added way too many numbers in my
staff report. 1,9
I believe 97.76.
I think I added an extra seven
um acres and then I don't remember
exactly how much the city owned one is,
but um looking at these parcels, the Fox
Ranch Lands is mostly just vacant ranch
land. Um
so the surrounding zoning out there,
it's all county LU. Um land around it is
either vacant or
has other ranch lands on it and is used
as a land.
So the closest city zone I believe is
actually just LI across uh HappyJack
down at the very southwest or southeast
corner. So through staff's analysis,
staff is recommending that that parcel,
so the Cox Ranch land parcel be zoned AG
as the assigned zoning.
Um which and as the chair mentioned the
next two items are going along with this
project as well and are the applicants
requested zone change and future land
use map amendment for um the actual
applicant parcel
the city-owned parcels uh with this
annexation because the water treatment
plan is right there and a portion of it
does become contiguous with the
annexation of that land. I know the
little square isn't contiguous. It is
actually separated by other county land,
but because it is city- owned, the city
can still annex it. Um,
so we did, uh, BOPU did want to annex
the land out here. So, we did ask if we
could bring this in with this
annexation. Uh, looking at the city zone
parcel, it's zoned LU in the county. Um,
close city zones, you'd have the AG,
LII, or BP zoning. Uh, but being this is
city-owned, the city, uh, we are
proposing that the assigned zoning just
be P public for that land.
So, with the two parcels being annexed,
um, the larger the parcels, staff would
recommend AG. For the city-owned parcel,
we would recommend T uh public zoning.
And due to remut uh due to meeting the
review criteria, staff does recommend
approval of the assigned zoning and I am
available for any questions.
>> Any st questions from the commission for
staff?
>> Yeah, Mr. Chair, through you.
I was also confused about the acre
number there too, but I don't I think
you have one extra nine. I think the
first nine doesn't belong. I think it's
in reality it's just less than 1,200
acres.
>> That could be correct. But yeah, I just
noticed that as I was going through. Um
>> but yeah, it it is over a thousand
acres. It is under the 1,200 because I
know when you add the city's parcel, I
know for my annexation staff report I
do, it's over 1,200 acres. That'd be
coming in with the full annexation.
So to clarify, we're talking about two
square miles, not over three square
miles,
I believe. So
okay,
Mr. I did did have one more uh substant
substantive question about the uh so
looking forward to the other
I guess the next item where we talk
about the uh urban service boundary.
This that that has no bearing on this.
This could still be reszoned to the
zoning districts you're asking for even
even before we've taken action on
changing the urban service boundary. Is
that correct
>> Mr. Chair? Yes, that is correct. So,
with an annexation, because this is the
parcel boundary, we do have to give it a
city zone when it's annexed, regardless
of the urban service boundary. It just
happens that the applicant is requesting
a different um zone district. Um so,
with that, we also needed a future land
use map amendment. So, we also amended
the urban service boundary at the same
time for basically that parcel. But with
an annexation uh one of the annexation
criteria does look at the urban service
boundary which I will be noting to
council that until the future land use
map goes through the process about 70%
of the parcel is within the urban
service boundary about 30% I believe is
outside of it um but the egg zoning say
the next two items don't go through the
egg zoning would still cover the parcel
um and would still be fine for the area
because It's it's the assigned zoning
portion. Um it's basically giving the
property kind of what the zoning is
currently and just allowing it to be
within city limits.
Okay. Are there any members of the
public who are here that wish to speak
to this item? Would you please read your
name and address for the record?
>> Uh through you, Mr. Chairman. Michael
White,
Marrying County, 665 Van Beerren Avenue.
Um, in respect to Connor's comments, um,
he stated that there's two parcels and
two owners. Um,
and maybe this is common practice for
the planning commission, but
to me it if it's two separate
properties, there should be u,
for lack of any other words, two
separate agendas and two separate
applicants.
One of course is the Cox Ranch. Uh, the
other one is uh the city of Cheyenne.
Well, the city of Cheyenne is the public
and uh
in addition to that, I know Connor made
the point about uh annexation, but to me
it's hard for the planning commission to
make a reasonable recommendation on a
vote when
a week from tonight there's public
hearing on this specific project. So
my feeling is planning commission should
um postpone this and allow both
applicants separately.
I guess what we're doing is piggybacking
this on uh another qu another question I
would have uh
did the board of public utilities board
approve were they the ones initiating
the annexation if I mean the the zone
change and if they did they go through
their board and approve that.
Um and the last comment I'd like to make
because I don't know how else to say it.
a zoning change. Also, you have to have
services out there.
Closest service for fire protection is
the county fire station. So, I don't
know if we're going to get into a turf
war again on who's going to acknowledge
that and that's probably something that
maybe you guys don't look at, but um
thank you for your time and appreciate
it.
>> Thank you. Is there are there any other
members of the public who are here to
speak on this item?
You got your name and uh address for the
record, please.
>> Uh chairman, plan commission members
Brad Evans, AVI, uh 11:03 Oldtown Lane.
Um just wanted to point out that this is
the same process we've done on every
annexation through the city for the last
20 years where the annexation and the
zone change go together simultaneously.
So the annexation and the zone change
will line up when we get in front of the
city council meeting. Um their their
meet their annexation decision and ours
will just line up one right after the
other. So, just wanted to make sure that
the planning commission understood we're
not doing this any differently um from a
standpoint of any annexation we've taken
through the process in the last 25 years
that I've been doing uh work in Larmy in
Larry County and the city of Cheyenne.
Um also um uh the this the process of
how this came forward is the Cox Ranch
uh did look uh they talked to the board
of public utility board of public
utilities about servicing the project.
They said yes, they could serve it. The
city of Cheyenne then said, "If we're
going to serve it, uh you need to annex
and bring it into the city of Cheyenne."
Um once we got into that process, then
the board asked if because we were
already submitting, already turning in
maps, we're going to be out in the area
surveying, asked if they could be
included with their land. Um and again,
as Connor pointed out, the the Board of
Public Utilities could have annex their
two parcels at any time. Their two
parcels are owned by the city. the state
statutes are very clear that you can
annex a city can annex their own
property. So, um the addition of them on
this map was just uh because we were
already out there in the field and
collecting the data. So, I'd be happy to
answer any questions um on this even
though this is the assigned zoning. So,
we're really here for the next two.
>> Thank you. And that is correct. This is
the assigned zoning so we're not to the
heavy lifting yet.
Are there any other members of the
public who are here to wish and wish to
comment on this item?
Are there any members of the public on
Zoom who wish to comment?
>> Mr. Chair, there are no members of the
public on Zoom any longer. Okay.
>> Going once, going twice. Public comment
is now closed
and
The chair is looking for a motion.
>> Chair, Commissioner Olsen. Uh, I move to
recommend the governing body approve the
assigned zoning for land west of
Roundtop Road and adjacent to HappyJack
Road to AG Agricultural and Public as
showing in shown in the attached zone
change map, noting that the project
meets the review criteria for approval.
>> I approve. Yeah, I'm sorry. I second it.
Okay. And I've got a got a motion by uh
Commissioner Olsen, seconded by
Commissioner Hibbons. Um and and just to
note for the general public, what we are
looking looking at here is if the city
annex votes to annex
some or all of this land, what will be
the applicable zoning
at the time of annexation?
Okay. Are there any other are there any
discussion by the commission?
Questions,
comments,
comments from commissioners on Zoom?
Hearing none, will staff please call
roll.
Daryl Hibbons.
>> Hi.
>> Lonnie Olsen.
>> I.
>> Tony Lair.
>> Hi.
>> Amy Hernandez.
I
>> Megan Connor
>> I
>> Mr. Chair that motion passes.
>> Thank you.
>> Will staff please read the next Are we
going to handle the two items together
or do we want to handle them
individually?
>> Mr. Chair, um if it's the commission's
preference if you would like basically
the applicant and staff to discuss both
these items together, we can. They will
have to have two separate motions. So we
we will have to do the motion
separately, but we could have the
discussion together. Um they do go
together, the zone changes contingent on
the future land use map amendment. So
I'm more than happy to discuss them
together. I'm sure our applicant is also
uh fine with discussing both together
because it might just make it easier to
discuss both points at the same time. Um
so that is the planning commission's
preference. I'm more than happy to read
both items into the record and we can
discuss them together.
>> And and is the applicant have
essentially one presentation or two?
Okay. Because I'm inclined to do them
separately, but let's let's read. Will
staff please read items F and G into the
record. Item F, PUDC-26-48,
Coxland future land use map amendment.
And then item G is PUDC-26-38
Coxland zoning map amendment.
>> Okay. Thank you. We have an applicant
chairman, planning commission members
Brad Evans, AVI agent uh for the owner
Cox Ranches and the applicants uh Tom
Glymmer and Jack O'Neal. Um before you
is a land use amendment and a a zone
change uh for the development of a a
business park in this area. Um as you
know recently we just uh went through
the process of get the city adopting a
business park zoning um that is uh
designated for areas like this. Um and
one of the reasons why we went through
the process of setting up sizes for the
business park if you remember it has to
be 320 acres minimum. um and those kind
of things. Uh again, uh the developer
and owner met with staff on uh making
sure that this could be um served with
uh sewer and water. Um we've started the
design of those services in this area as
well. Um with the fact that the BOPU
said that they could serve it serve this
area. Um
if you look at the current land use
amendment, it does talk about uh
residential areas um and expansion and
that is very similar to what uh was in
the areas where we did project equality
to the south of this um as the business
park has grown uh to the west. It has
just uh been continually uh expanded the
land use amendment to the west and it is
most of it is inside the urban service
boundary. Um, again, uh, looking for BP
zoning, uh, after the land use amendment
has been moved forward. Happy to answer
any questions on either one with the,
uh, commission.
Are there any questions for the
applicant from the commission?
applicant from the commissioners who are
with us via Zoom?
Hearing none, will staff please
read its report.
Chair, members of the commission, Conor
Planning and Development Department.
The item before you is a future land use
or yeah, future land use map amendment.
Um, this amendment looks at also
extending the urban service boundary.
Uh, this is for the same project as our
last item. So, it is west of Round Top
Road and adjacent to HappyJack Road.
Again, uh, it's the highlighted area.
This does not include the city-owned
land. So, this is just the applicant's
request for both these items. Um so it
is just the Cox ranch lands but this
future land use map amendment uh it
would look at extending the urban
service boundary. Um as you can kind of
see even on the future land use map if I
go to the applicants map you can see a
little bit better but that dashed pink
line on the left map um that is the
urban service boundary. It is just a
straight line currently doesn't follow
any of the parcel boundaries. Um so
basically the land outside of that also
doesn't have a future land use attached
to it at this time. So with this
amendment it would extend the urban
service boundary to basically just match
the parcel line of the parcel itself.
And then it would also be looking at
giving the land that doesn't have a
future land use the mixeduse employment
designation and also changing the urban
transition residential portion to
mixeduse employment.
So, with the future land use map
amendment, um
this does coincide with the second item,
which is the applicant requesting the
business park zone district. Uh with the
BP zone or I guess with the future land
use amendment to mixeduse employment, it
would accommodate the zone change, which
is the second item to business park.
Um, as I mentioned, part of the property
is outside the urban service boundary
and has no future land use designation.
Um, with our future land use map, there
are cases where you can see it where the
future land use is not just a square box
around Cheyenne. It does follow parcel
boundaries, especially on the east side
of Cheyenne. Um, so this isn't uncommon
to extend the urban service boundary to
follow parcel boundaries rather than
just be a straight line.
portion of uh the property uh is
currently urban service or sorry urban
transition residential. The urban
transition residential category uh along
with the rural residential category
uh provides a general transition from
the urbanized areas of Cheyenne uh of
the Cheyenne area to the rural areas
um on the periphery.
It does include uh existing houses and
neighborhoods as well as some planned
and uh recent new growth areas.
The mixeduse employment um designation,
we do look at that as being kind of more
on the kind of exterior of the
community, kind of further out. Um,
usually with mixeduse employment, it is
uh a land use that would be used for
kind of larger pieces of land like this
if they are looking to develop with uh
larger business park type uh
developments
in this area.
There is mixeduse employment to the
south. Um all to the south is basically
well
portion of it to the southwest I would
say is uh or southeast is North Range
Business Park. Uh there is land outside
of North Range Business Park that does
have the same designation does not
currently annexed or within city limits
but is also on the future land use map
is potentially in the future developing
with some sort of mixeduse employment.
To the north you do have agricultural
rule um and no designation.
the south you also have some that is no
designation.
To the east is urban transition
residential and then to the west uh
that's all outside the urban service
boundary and has no designation.
Through staff's review,
we did find that um or we do believe
that the mixeduse employment does fit
the property out here. Um some of the
policies that it does meet would be
flexibility to response to market
demand, um recruit new employers and
location for heavy industrial use.
Um, specifically with that last policy,
um,
it does talk about, uh, having kind of
these larger kind of industrial uses be
on the exterior and then also being able
to have kind of that
uh, direct distribution um, and being
able to get to the various uh, major
through affairs.
So with that, Steph does recommend
approval of the future land use map
amendment uh for this property.
Going on to the zone change itself being
the same property.
Um
again staff recommended approval uh for
that assigned zoning of AG. The
applicant is requesting the BP zone. Um,
similar points, this is near a business
park. Uh, it is almost an extension of a
business park. Our business park
definition did require 320 acres
basically to be zoned BP. This property
can do that on its own even if it wasn't
adjacent to the business park. Um,
at this time, staff hasn't been
presented any final plans for how the
property would develop. It can develop
as multiple parcels. Um, it could
develop as one parcel. It again could be
a similar business park to what North
Range is out there already.
Um, but it does have the acreage to
uh basically be recommended for approval
for business park zone.
the
without the future land use map
amendment um staff wouldn't be
recommending approval of the BP zone um
out there it is the
urban transition as I had mentioned
um
but with going to the mixeduse
employment
One of the zone districts that mixed use
employment zone would consider would be
that BP zone as the BP zone is a mix of
our LI HI and CB zone districts. So it
does allow for commercial uses. It
allows for light industrial, a little
bit of heavy industrial
um
again. This is on the exterior of
basically the city boundaries. So, it's
on the edge, which
that's also something else the BP zone
district looked at was being those
larger parcels being kind of the
exterior of the community.
So, again, staff would recommend
approval of the zoning map amendment as
well as the future land use map
amendment.
And with that, I am available for any
questions.
>> Thank you, Chair.
>> All right, Commissioner Olsen.
>> Uh, I got a couple of questions for
staff, and this is backing up to the
future land use map amendment. Uh, the
first one was, uh, correct me if I'm
wrong, but doesn't the future land use
map amendment also have to go through
the county commissioners as well,
>> Mr. Chair, through you. So with the
future
>> confused
>> kind of um so it does basically future
land use map amendments do have to go to
county commissioners um in this case
we're sending these to county
commissioners as comment only. The
reason for that is we will basically
after tonight the future land use map
amendment will have a delayed submittal
to council. So future land use map
amendments go as resolutions.
Basically they only have to go through
uh first reading committee second
reading second reading is their decision
annexation assigned zoning zoning map
amendment all have three readings and
take a longer time.
So by us delaying the middle to council
everything will line up and be approved
the same night and by being approved the
same night it will basically the future
land use map amendment will also be
pulled off of consent and will have to
be considered in a different order on
the agenda. Um, but that will allow it
to be considered after the land is
annexed.
By doing that, it does not go to county
commissioners for also their approval.
It just goes for comment because any
land that is within city limits just
goes to county commissioners for
comment. Anything that is in the county
um would go through both jurisdictions.
So,
we've done this before. Um it's a lot of
timing and also kind of having to work
with the clerk's office to get
everything lined up on the final agenda,
but um it would not require the
basically concurrence of the county
commissioners. It just goes to them for
comment, which it is going to county
both future land use map amendments, I
should note, that are on tonight's
agenda go to county commissioners
tomorrow. So that way we have comments
just just in case they have comments we
have those for council
and chair I have one more or a different
area but still pertaining to the future
land use map amendment and that's about
the urban service area. Uh I know
previously it was just the north south
line which kind of seems uh pretty
simple but I'm just curious if there was
any sort of like a serviceability
analysis of how far that could be
extended. I know you can pump water up
but at some point it's going to be cost
too much to pump it up. So, I'm just
curious if staff considered doing that
along the whole area just since you're
opening up this can of worms or
if there's a reason that it wasn't
considered
muru and maybe the end will answer this
as well, but staff did not consider um
extending it more in this area. We were
mostly just looking at the applicants
requesting this area be changed and
because you're looking at a parcel that
was half inside the service bound or
more than half but there was a portion
that was outside of it. Um and also
requesting a future land use
designation. We were just looking at
specifically their parcel. Um now if
another parcel did want to come in and
do the same thing, maybe there would be
more analysis. A lot of it is going to
also hinge on what does B the OPU think.
Um they haven't had a lot of comments on
any of these applications. As the
applicant mentioned, they've had many
discussions on what they can service on
this property, how they can service it.
It sounds like they're in design and
they'll be working with BOPU. So, it
sounds like it is serviceable to a
point. I don't know what point that is
to, but um
according to the applicant of BOPU, they
they can service it. So, no, we we only
looked at this parcel because that's
what was being requested.
Um staff hasn't done a full-blown
analysis of our urban service boundary.
We are working on getting the RFP out
still for the full uh plan Cheyenne
update, so maybe that might be something
that gets looked at at that point. Um
but as for just this project, we just
looked at this this particular parcel.
>> I've got a question for staff as we're
pondering. I'm
like Commissioner Olsen. I'm I'm
thinking of
of just the
future land use map uh amendment.
Um I know we're I know we're expanding
it kind of peace meal here.
You just mentioned you just mentioned
that the RFP for a complete update is
out and and I would assume that
that that
complete update
would
would address not only this but but
other similarly situated, similarly
elevated land that's outside our ur
urban service boundary.
that
would be at the same elevation, same
lever level of sewer ability, it would
come in and
up there. There's a kind of the adjacent
land that I'm I'm really concerned about
that lies immediately to the east of
this is is marked yellow, but my eyes
aren't good enough to read what the key
says that is. Um,
it's urban transition residential. Okay,
thank you.
Um I'm glad to see that. But as as we're
talking about expanding our amenmenting
our map here,
I've got the same concern that I had
when the project, I believe it was
Cosmo, came in and we we amended our
future land use map to convert
several square miles worth of future
residential
to what became a business park. And I'm
assuming this is going to eventually be
a data center, too. Uh and and now we're
looking at at trying to
bring almost a collar of of of
business parks around to the edge edge
of Cheyenne to the west kind of form a
boundary there.
I'm I'm concerned about this type of an
amendment just kind of the cumulative
effect cumulative effects of of of some
of these amendments that we're we're
looking at. And
what's going to be the plan
if we if anything that's sewable
we build out as business parks
when we've got a housing shortage in the
community. And I think I know we've got
one coming up that there's some push
back to an amendment that would cut down
on available housing, but
I think part of what we're dealing with
here is is amend amending the future
land use map to accommodate this.
And I'm concerned about the cumulative
effect. Was there any discussion or is
it does does staff have
something to soo my concerns about about
this
in light of what we've done in the past
and what we're looking at doing in the
future for future land use and
residential accommodation.
So, Mr. Chair staff did look again like
you mentioned there's and I know of more
future land use map amendments that'll
be coming forward. Um so staff has had
to look at areas and determine
how those could still move forward and
develop in certain ways. Is residential
still something that we foresee out at
this location? Um, one of the things I
was just actually going back to my staff
report is strict adherence to the plan.
Um, as I noted in the staff report that
while the land could be developed with
residential, it is on the edge of the
community where the high level of
services typically expected with urban
residential development could be
challenging to expand out here. Um,
alternatively, the area could develop
with large acreage ranchut style
development in the county. Uh, however,
such development is not optimal for
areas within the urban service boundary.
So, we had to take a look at areas like
this where they're they're on this is
the edge of our urban service boundary
um as opposed to some of the other
future land use map amendments where
they're not on the very edge of our
urban service boundary and determine
what would be the most optimal for the
edge of the community at this point.
And again, it goes back to if we expect
this to develop with residential, is it
going to be ranchettes? Is it going to
be urban style? But then if it's urban
style, you are looking at a lot more
challenging development uh for this
area.
And I think that's how we've kind of
been looking at
more of these future land use map
amendments is their location,
what is surrounding it.
Do we believe that area is going to
continue to develop with residential
and what impacts that would have
just kind of a followup. Um, looking at
what we've got immediately to the to the
east, we've got the
got the residential area and then
there's what looks to be like it used to
be part of the same ranch before there
apparently was some sort of an ownership
split. Did we get any kind of a comment
specifically
from the landowner immediately to the
east of this
regarding this action?
>> Mr. Chair, through you the land owner
directly to the east is the same land
owner
So, and I might be able to show it on a
Yeah. So, the parcel that is directly
east, the larger portion that is not
kind of the subdivision is the exact
same land owner. So, it is also the Cox
family.
Um, and then you get to the subdivision,
and I'll let the applicant maybe address
it a little bit more, but then you get
to the subdivision, which I have had
comments from the subdivision, but it
was mostly around that subdivision
thinking the city's annexing them.
>> Okay. And just for a point of
clarification, if it's the same,
according to the assessor's website,
there's two different land owners.
They're both Coxes, but I wanted to get
some clarification.
>> I can let the Yes.
>> applicant speak to that.
>> Um, before we get to the applicant, are
there any more questions for staff from
the commission? Commissioner Lair,
>> Mr. Chair through you, I have a couple
maybe technical semantic questions. Um,
the first is just a a process thing. I'm
looking at the recommended motion and it
reads move to approve the resolution
amending. Now, this commission is not
actually approving a resolution, right?
The resolution is one that will be
approved by the governing body. So, it
seems to me like it should read like our
normal motion where we recommend to the
governing body.
>> So, Mr. Chair, in this case, um I
believe this is kind of similar to a
preliminary plat where you actually
approve it and then council either
affirms the approval or I mean if you
recommend or I guess if you deny it,
they can still approve it. Um it changes
some of the language in our resolution
itself. But I believe in this case in
the way that it is written within plan
Cheyenne the planning commission does
actually approve the uh
>> but it's not the final approval but it's
one of several
>> correct it and that's where I think it
goes to if if this had to go to county
commissioners there would have to be
multiple different approvals
um that it would go through but in this
case
you are actually approving and then
council would be the final approval.
Um,
but that is my understanding. I did have
Seth look at my staff report. So, and I
believe both staff reports are written
the same way. Um, but we did look at the
language and had to kind of figure that
out on how that works. Um, with the two
items we have on the agenda uh with
those going to council, but it is
planning commission is moving to
approve.
Okay. So the other really picky
technical question if you go to like the
last page of the land use report that
item that and what I'm talking about in
particular is the urban service boundary
and how it's depicted on that uh
picture and it so you see the kind of
before
picture on the left it doesn't it
doesn't quite coincide with the edge of
that uh planning boundary which seems
odd because when I looked at the GIS map
online, it looks like it does coincide.
And then in the uh proposed
they they did make the proposed urban
service boundary coincide with that the
jogs on that parcel except for the very
northern piece of it where it is inset a
little bit. And I didn't know if that
was deliberate or just kind of a
drafting thing. I guess that that's the
question is what's going on with that
urban service boundary especially in the
proposed part.
>> Mr. Chair through you I'll let the
applicant maybe answer the mapping
portion
but my my understanding is that we would
have the urban service boundary
basically run along the line of where
the future land use map ends.
If I may, so to clarify, do we think
that the urban service boundary is
depicted is intended to lie
at the parcel boundary even though it
looks like it's not along that?
I think that's what's being asked.
Mr. Chairman, I I guess Brad Evans, I
guess I don't I'm not quite following
exactly what
>> Okay, looking at the this reminds me of
the state of Texas, the kind of picture
of it with the panhandle at the top. So,
if we think about the little panhandle
piece at the very top, why is the urban
service boundary
>> jogged in a little bit? It isn't it
isn't right along the edge of that
purple, but it's in a little ways.
Whereas the rest of that boundary, it
follows it exactly.
Well, the Mr. Chairman 3u I guess the it
it would probably need to j just a
little bit to the west at the top in the
purple area
but uh these these are just exhibit M I
mean these aren't survey level maps and
as we go through so that can be updated
if the if the the uh commission
uh requested on the top end of there. Um
>> Mr. Chair that's fine. That it's kind of
what I thought. I didn't know if there
was something some subtle thing I was
missing and not understanding. But yeah,
that's fine if it's just a matter of the
drafting isn't quite precise.
>> Mr. Chairman, I'd like to go back to
Lonnie had a question and you had a
question. So,
>> questions for staff.
>> Chair, I might have one more and it's
>> then we'll then we'll call you back to
address. And this is going to be kind of
piggybacking off of the chair's question
and it's just a more of a philosophical
question about where the planning office
sees how like residential housing growth
in our community. I as the chair was
kind of mentioning we are getting
constricted. Our northern boundaries are
all ranchets which are very hard to
redevelop into more dense housing.
The east is kind of showing those trends
as well and then we're kind of looping
ourselves around. So, I'm just curious
where does staff foresee it? I know that
we had sweet grass and there's a little
blip there that we can maybe get out,
but it seems to be getting more and more
condensed down and it's just we have I
think eight plus studies that are saying
that we're in a housing crunch and with
all this development of these large
campuses, it's also going to be more
people needing a place to stay. And we
have the Sentinel project. So, just
more philosophical, not
just because it's
Mr. chair through you um to Commissioner
Olson. I will say there has been
especially in the past couple of months
a lot of discussions in our office um
about all of this about where we see
housing going
um how can how is the city going to
expand um and things of that nature.
Just again because as you mentioned with
all the development going on especially
the large data centers um
we've even had to start looking at
putting a map together to see where all
these proposed data centers are going to
go to really see how that is
constricting. Um,
but again, I think part of what we're
looking at with this one is it does come
down to
do we foresee kind of urban development
within the urban service boundary at
this extent um to the edge of what our
urban service boundary is. Um
whereas we do have other locations that
are more kind of closer to where we
currently have urban development that we
would hope would continue to develop
with residential rather than have it be
out this far on the extreme edge. Um
so I think that's kind of where staff
has been going with these is this again
I think I've said it multiple times this
go back this goes back to this is on the
edge of our urban service boundary. It's
at the very edge of where we believe is
serviceable.
Um,
and already with this one, we are
extending the urban service boundary a
little bit to accommodate the parcel.
Um, but right now this is the extent of
that urban service boundary and is on
the edge. So we we were
looking at this one and believe that it
would be fine for this area to go to
mixeduse employment um
rather than stay with that urban
transition.
And one last question then we'll we'll
get here. Um,
is is there any comment? Does the Air
Force base care
that were doing things to to the west of
them and encircling
encircling it? Did we hear any feedback,
any comment? Was the Air Force base even
part of the notification
of this process?
>> Mr. share through you that I can say
that no, the Air Force base was not part
of the notification process. Um, even
that neighborhood that's to the east
wasn't part of the notification process.
Um, our notification process is 300 ft
from the property. 300 ft gets you
slightly into again what I would say is
the same property owner, but I'll let
the applicant explain the property
ownerships there. Um,
so no, the Air Force Base hasn't made
comment. Um,
my recent memory, and Director Bloom can
correct me if I'm wrong, there's still
discussions going on with the Air Force
base about annexation of the base. Um, I
don't know where that is in the process.
There's been discussions, I think, for
many, many years of annexing the base.
Um, but I believe that's all usually
tied up with the federal government. Um,
so no, they have not had any comment on
this. They haven't made comment. I don't
know if they're even aware of it. I
don't honestly know if they'll really
care if they're being encircled because
again, when it comes to the city zoning
regulations or any zoning regulations,
they don't apply to the base. Even if it
was annexed,
it turns into basically they get our
military zone district and we wouldn't
have any say. Um, when it comes to base
stuff, that's generally how I've seen
it. So,
I don't know. I mean, we've got
residential that's adjacent to the base,
kind of at that north east portion
that's within city limits. So, there's
there's already city limits along most
of their east side.
Okay. Thank you. Any other questions for
staff? Would the applicant like to
please address some of the questions
that were posed to staff?
Uh yes, chairman Brad Emmens again, AVI
agent for the owner and applicant. A
little history about the
urban service boundary in the zoning out
here. Uh when this was originally set
up, it was basically a square around the
city of Cheyenne. It was just an area
that the MO uh called the urban service
boundary. I don't even think it was
really discussed from a standpoint of
water, sewer. Um it was an area that the
no uh dictated and it was I believe a
four mile square. So it goes from
basically Horse Creek to this western
boundary to Chalk Bluff Road to now
what's Archer. So that's kind of how
this original boundary got set. It had
nothing really to do with sewer, water,
um those kind of things. as we've moved
forward, obviously those things have
become more much more critical and and
and we're discussing them on an on these
things. I mean, from a sewer standpoint,
you can go as far west as you want as
long as the sewer pipelines are large
enough to get them back to the to the um
to the treatment plants or you could put
a new treatment plant further west. Um,
basically those are things that are are
uh being looked at and and actually I
think the commission has a good point
the long-term development of um all of
Cheyenne and it do we go to another
basin at some point this basin is going
to be completely full and you have to
probably go to
um child's draw or you might have to go
to a basin to the south if you want to
keep developing at uh urban standards.
So, I think that's a question that needs
to be looked at and the city I think
with their um comp plan amendment stuff
and things that are going forward that
should be one of their primary uh
discussion points is where where the
long term we need to be thinking way
longer on some future things than um you
know 10 15 20 years. Those are kind of
50-year discussions. Um at the I mean I
I look at what's out there residentially
and this would be my opinion. Um not but
when you have Sweet Grass, Whitney
Ranch, Saddle Ridge is still ongoing and
the amount of building permits that are
built out pulled each year, there's a
vast amount of residential areas still
available. Are they going to end up
someday not being all there? That that
that's going to be true. Someday they'll
all fill up. So I think the long range
planning of all of these areas are
something the city needs to be doing.
But at this point in time, um these
areas um would not be uh urban full
urban residential development this far
out west. I mean like what Connor's
talking about of if you put that many
homes out here so far from where the
current fire stations are, police
stations, there's a lot of demand and
these business parks don't put near the
demand on those public services as as
residential does. So, um, so I think
that's kind of the stuff on the western
boundary and, uh, the ownership group,
this was owned by one family. It has,
completed some probate stuff and
finished up and so they are finished
with that. And I believe it's two
separate. Uh, the eastern is one Cox
family, the western is the other Cox
family. However, uh there is a parcel
with this annexation and zone change
that is owned by the eastern parcel. Um
they own that little bit that's on the
south side of HappyJack Road and a
little bit that's on the north side of
HappyJack Road. So, um both both people
are part of this project. Um so they are
aware of what's going on and are okay
with it um from that standpoint.
Um,
so
I think those were were there any other
specific questions that
I missed?
Okay, thank you. And I believe we'll
open up for public discussion. Are there
any members of the public who are still
here to talk to and to speak on this on
this issue?
Now that I think we've probably got the
issue that prior comment was intended to
address
uh through you, Mr. Chairman, Michael
White, uh 665 Van Beern Avenue, Larry
County.
I guess the one of the questions I have
and I don't mean to put Connor on the
spot. Um
I remember some of the other areas that
were part of the county
and the city will say where Brad's
familiar with Whitney Ranch on this
specific topic.
And my understanding was the
commissioners had to do the approval of
it. So I'm confused. So, I'm going to
ask the commissioners tomorrow on this
why they don't have to put it up for
full agenda.
Um, my comment would be,
let's be honest, um, let's get Brad up
here to tell us exactly what the land's
going to be used for. You guys talk
about residential housing. Well, let's
put it out here in the final deal.
What's the land going to be used for?
Now, maybe this is not the right time
for it, but I think it is. Thank you.
Are there any other members of the
public who wish to speak to this item?
Are there any members of the public who
are on Zoom who wish to speak to this
item?
Public comment going once, going twice.
Public comment is closed.
I'd invite the applicant to come to the
podium and address questions raised at
public comment.
>> Mr. Chairman Brads, AVI agent for the
applicant and the owners. Uh currently
it's going to be a business park with
the possibility of a data center that
would go into that area. Um so
that's not confirmed or finalized or
anything like that, but currently
they're trying to develop it as a
business park. Um, so
if uh again I believe and if you want me
to answer the question for Connor that
the city is following the rules that
they've done on on these as we've moved
through and I believe it's uh directly
in the plan Cheyenne document is where
it says that it uh goes to the county
for comment only.
And to clarify to the county for comment
only in the event that it is annexed to
the city. Is that correct?
>> Mr. Chair, um just so I can make it
clarif clear enough for the um for both
the public and for the record, let me
open up my
memo I sent to the county commissioners
because I believe it even references the
section of plan Cheyenne.
Okay. So, the I'll just go ahead and
I'll read what's in the memo. Um
according to uh plan amendment process
and procedure section outlined in the
introduction section of plan Cheyenne,
any proposed plan Cheyenne amendment
will go before the governing body that
will have jurisdiction for comment uh go
to the governing body that will not have
jurisdiction for comment only.
Uh example, a uh proposal to amend land
use uses within city limits goes to the
county uh first for common only and then
basically I state that the current
proposed plan amendment will edit the
future land use map amendment and goes
into kind of what that is. But in plan
Cheyenne itself, it basically states
that the amendment will only go before
the governing body of jurisdiction.
Basically
before the governing body that will not
have jurisdiction for comment only. So I
guess it would be the same thing if it
was a county zoning or county plan
amendment. It would only go to city
council for comment only. Um but again
because this is going to be within city
limits and we delay the actual approval
of this future land use map amendment to
the last to basically after the
annexation and it's not approved until
after the annexation. It only goes to
the county commissioners for comment
only. They do not actually have it on
their agenda as something they vote on.
And that does again that does come
directly from plan Cheyenne in the
process and procedure section as
outlined in the introduction of that
document.
>> Okay. Thank you. And then for
clarification, anything we're doing here
is contingent upon
annexation by the city council.
>> Mr. Chair, yes. So with your
recommendation, So with your
recommendation,
council won't see that until basically
the end. Actually, I think they won't
even see it till the beginning of May.
Um is when it basically will be at
public service committee for is it May
4th? I believe
>> should be the first May first. So May
May 4th would be the first Monday where
this will actually be discussed in front
of council
>> because then it will line up with the
final reading of the annexation on May
11th and then this will not be on
consent. The way that it would work on
the agenda which I have to again work
out with the clerk's office is we would
have the annexation
assigned zoning. This would be pulled
from consent. They would have to
I forgot what it's called, but they
would have to basically amend the agenda
or use Robert's rules to basically move
this item from where it is under
resolutions to be before the zone change
be approved and then the zone change
ordinance be read and acted upon.
So, as a followup, I think we I would
like to have us have a conversation
about even our action for the for the
record, our action would be we're acting
contingent on future annexation because
I think we're powerless without it.
>> Correct. Okay. Much like the last item
we had.
>> Yes. So that's
>> with these items, you're basically
acting as you're making recommendations
based on if this property gets annexed.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Um I think everything's closed. I think
we're to the point of a
motion by the commission
for debate discussion.
The chair will accept a motion.
>> Mr. Chair and this is of course just on
item F which is the future land use
amendment.
>> Yes, we only do want to do one at a
time.
>> I move to approve the resolution
amending the future land use plan for
1,193.4
acres of land west of Roundtop Road and
north of HappyJack Road as shown in the
future land use map provided. Adding
land to the urban service boundary,
designating that land mixeduse
employment
and
changing land adjacent to that addition
from urban transition residential to
mixeduse employment.
And before we get too far, is that the
right number of acres? Is that the
proper acre count? Okay.
I'll second that.
>> Got a second.
Is there any discussion? Any desire to
amend
the account for
the cond contingency of non-nexation
or anything like that?
But chair, I personally think it we
would be fine not having that
contingency because I don't foresee city
council moving forward with approving
this if it's not annexed.
Feel like it would be kind of outside of
their lane to amend it without having
the jurisdiction.
>> And Mr. Chair, I should note that if the
annexation wasn't approved for some
reason, I would probably get up and also
tell them right away, one, don't approve
the assigned zoning, then don't approve
any of the zonings that come after it.
And I will say they've they understand
that
>> Mr. Chair, I think just the thing Connor
went through with plan Cheyenne and the
rules of procedure for that I think
makes it impossible for the city council
to change this land use area without
amending or without annexing the land.
county commission then could change the
land use out there because it would
still be under their jurisdiction but
not under the cities.
>> I guess my concern is whether or not
we've got jurisdiction to make this
recommendation absent acknowledgement
that this is contingent on annexation
at this level.
>> Mr. Chair, we've we've done this
numerous times this way. So, I guess if
we decide now that we've got that we
need to slow down and get these things
lined out in order, we've done a lot of
them. I think exactly this way.
Any further discussion
from count from the commission? Any
discussion or comment from those of us
who are on Zoom?
Hearing none.
Uh, will staff please call roll for item
F.
Megan Connor.
>> No.
>> Lonnie Olsen.
>> I
Tony Lair.
>> Hi.
>> Daryl Hibbons.
>> I
Amy Hernandez.
>> Mr. Mr. Chair, that motion passes.
>> Okay. Thank you.
And now the chair is looking for a
motion on item G.
Chair,
I move to approve the reszoning of
1,197.76
acres of land west of Roundtop Road and
north of HappyJack Road to BP Business
Park as shown in the attached zone
change map, noting that the project
meets the review criteria for approval.
>> I second.
>> Got a motion and a second.
Uh discussion by the commission,
comments, desired amendments,
any comment or discussion from those of
us on on Zoom?
>> Yeah, Mr. Chairman, I just would like to
see us examine other data centers or a
good idea around cities and it's blown
up all over the internet. I see it
across the country and quite frankly I
find it terrifying. So it's going to be
a big no for me because I find that um
business park is analogous with data
center disconcerning for me.
>> Thank you.
>> Any other discussion by the commission?
Seeing none,
Mr. Chair,
staff, will staff please call roll for
uh item G.
Amy Hernandez.
>> Hi.
>> Honey Olsen.
>> Daryl Hibbons.
>> Hi.
>> Megan Connor.
>> No.
>> Tony Lair.
>> I.
>> Mr. Chair. That motion passes.
>> Okay. Thank you. Is there any desire for
a brief break? We've been at this for
couple of hours. Chair I would entertain
a fivem minute break.
>> Okay.
Okay. With that uh meeting is in recess
for 5 minute. We can reconvene at 15
Okay, it is 8:15 and the planning
commission will
reconvene.
Staff, please read item H. And do we
have our two members back to Zoom? Okay.
Okay. Okay. Well, with that, uh, will
staff please read item H into the
record.
What Charles had to say. Um, item H,
PUDC-26-40
O'Neal Edge Expedited Plat.
>> Okay. Do we have an applicant?
>> Uh, chair, members of the planning
commission, good evening, Brandon Swain.
This is going to be brief. Mr. Sers has
me on a 60-second timer up here. Um,
first in full disclosure, we have had
five members of the public leave. Uh,
the first three gentlemen were just here
to sit in. The last two were here for
the Cox development. Um uh what you have
here before you is a development I'm
calling O'Neal Edge. Uh
I think maybe
uh December of 24 possibly I was here
for Fifth Street Towns. This is a simply
just a duplication of that product. Uh
the development at Fifth Street Fifth
Street Towns, excuse me, is complete. Uh
four um four units total, two pairs of
twin homes. Um on video saying I'd hold
the price at 250,000 and that's what
they're listed for. We sold two of them.
um you've got to carve out these
affordable housing opportunities
somewhere. Often it comes from infill
often on tight lots. It's just the
nature of the business. Uh this one in
particular, uh the lots from east to
west are um 60 ft deep. The fifth street
town project was 42. Um so not as much
relief needed for this product. However,
I would be remiss not to mention that I
am asking for parking relief on this.
Typically units are required to have two
parking spaces per unit. Uh these units
don't have garages. It's all on street.
So far, it's working out fine with the
other project. Uh, this parcel was also
slightly larger than my last one as it
included two lots. So, we have a fifth
remainder lot that's going to be
fronting Fifth Street. Uh, could be
single family, could be duplex, but that
one will have alley loaded parking. So,
not anticipating that's going to
exacerbate the parking issue at all.
That being said, I'm available for any
questions.
>> Commission, any questions for the
applicant?
Commissioners on Zoom
questions.
Okay. Thank you.
>> Staff, please read your report into the
record.
>> Mr. Chair, commissioners, Morgan Dennis,
Planning and Development. This is an
expedited plat for 0.3 acre parcel
located southwest of the intersection of
West Fifth Street and O'Neal Avenue.
This lot is currently vacant. Um, the
purpose of this plot is to create five
lots for residential development.
The future land use map designates this
parcel as urban residential. Zoning for
this parcel is MR medium density
residential.
Surrounding development in the area is
primarily residential.
Four of the lots proposed fall within
the SD3 lot type and the remaining lot
is considered DD7.
All lots proposed are buildable in the
MR zone. On the preliminary map uh plat
map there is not a water or sewer
service easement. This easement has been
requested by the board of public
utilities prior to signing the this
prior to signing. This easement will
need to be added to the final plat map.
Uh staff recommends approval with the
condition that the water and sewer
easement is added prior to signing. I
stand for questions.
Any
questions for staff by the commission?
>> Commissioners on Zoom. Questions for
staff?
>> Chair, I have a question but for the
applicant after we get through staff. I
just thought of
>> Okay. Hearing none.
Um
I'll take I'll take the question for for
the applicant.
>> Thank you, Chair Chair. uh to the
applicant. I'm just curious with your uh
previous development if any of the
surrounding land owners have mentioned
or commented on the development. I know
kind of these things are hard to
visualize. So once they're built, you
can kind of see it. I'm just curious if
there's been any input by those
surrounding. I know it's not pertaining
to this application, but I know it's
another infill that has similar
uh Sure. So, the um development that I
just finished, again, Fifth Street
Towns, uh this is on the um southeast
corner of Snyder and Fifth Street,
heavily trafficked area. I think first
pe people were shocked that I could get
four units in there. Um this is going to
sound like I'm blowing smoke, but to be
honest with you, I've got nothing but
compliments um on it. It's it's been
very wellreceived. Um I mean, yeah, like
I just had keys replaced, so I called
the lock shop. the guy called me the day
after and wants me to run a project for
him. So, I guess that's kind of the
nature of of uh how it's going, but
overall it's been wellreceived. Um I
don't know, their quartz counters tile
and stuff. I just have a bare minimum
that I do, but I think it tends to
exceed what what most single family
standards are, especially for that area.
So, it's been mostly wellreceived.
Tenants are happy. Um again, I'm I'm not
the owner. Maybe this is just feedback
that I've got from from the people who
have purchased the units. So, yeah,
happy to address any other questions.
Any other questions?
Any other questions for staff or the
applicant from the commission?
Okay, I'll know now open this uh item up
for public comment.
Are there any members of the public
present who wish to comment?
Are there any members of the public on
Zoom who wish to comment?
Hearing none, public comment is now
closed.
I'm looking for a motion.
Mr. Chair, I move to approve the O'Neal
Edge preliminary plat advancing the
final plat to the governing body with
staff recommended conditions.
>> It's been moved. Do I hear a second?
>> Second.
>> Got a motion and a second.
This item is available for discussion by
the commission.
Comments from commission. Discussion.
Amendments.
Commissioners on Zoom. Any comments?
Discussion hearing? None. Will staff
please call RO.
>> Megan Connor.
>> I.
>> Lonnie Olsen. I
>> Daryl Hibbons.
>> I Tony Lair.
>> I
Amy Hernandez.
>> Mr. Chair, that motion passes. Okay.
Thank you.
Will staff please read item I into the
record? And I I guess we can handle both
I and J presentations together. They
appear to come. Mr. Chair, that is I'll
leave that up to the commission, but
yes, both items are related to one
another um is the same project. So, if
we want to conduct that the same way we
conducted F and G,
>> we can definitely do that.
>> Okay. So, I will read both item I and J
into the record and we'll discuss
discuss those uh together.
>> I misspoke.
>> Sorry.
>> Yes.
>> Item I PUDC dash
Nope, you're good. PUDC-26-59
Stanberry Farms future land use map
amendment and item J PUDC-26-53
Stan Stanberry Farms zoning map
amendment.
Okay. Will you
Oh, I'm sorry. I thought I was asking
for for the report. Will
will the applicant Do we have an
applicant?
I'm sorry. I'm falling asleep here. Will
the applicant please
present items I and J?
>> Mr. Chairman, through you, John Sers's
agent for True Great Land Development. I
I did want to point out I wasn't asked
if I wanted to present both at the same
time like you did, Mr.
But I'm okay with that just to keep us
rather do them individually.
>> No, no. We're going to We all like to
get home sometime tonight.
Uh I'm here asking for the future land
use map amendment for a parcel of land
located near Southwest Drive. Currently,
this property is affected by three
different zoning designations. Light
industrial exist, agricultural,
residential, and agricultural. Our
request is to coordinate the parcels
under a single LI zoning designation
which is consistent with several
adjacent and nearby properties. The
parcel is bounded by Interstate 80 to
the north, Burlington Northern Santa Fe
Railroad to the east and Southwest Drive
to the west and vacant land to the
south. Due to this location and
surrounding context, we have received
interest in potential projects that
align with LI zoning in a mixeduse
employment classification.
However, this request does differ from
the future land use map which currently
designates the area as mixeduse
residential. I would note that actual
development patterns in this area have
already diverged from that designation.
For example, properties north of
Interstate 80 are zoned li even where
the future land use map shows mixeduse
residential, mixeduse commercial, and
open space to the north. To the east, B
beyond the Burlington Northern Railroad
corridor, properties are zoned li under
a mixeduse employment designation. And
to the south, existing uses include
storage facilities, homebased
businesses, and other non-residential
activities.
Because of these existing conditions, it
would be incomplete to say this area is
developing consistently with the future
land use map.
There is also a jurisdictional
complication between city and the county
immediately south of our parcels which
further impacts coordinated planning and
long-term development in this area.
Additionally, our in property is
encumbered by overhead power lines and
berry gas lines that utility pro
providers have indicated will not be
relocated. These constraints
significantly limit the feasibility of
mixed use residential development and
were not fully accounted for in the
future land use map.
While the future land use map is an
important planning tool, it is not
static. There are circumstances where
amendments are appropriate and we
believe this is one of those cases.
In regards to city comments on criteria,
we respectfully disagree with the
staff's conclusion that the proposed
future future land use map amendment
largely does not comply. We're at a 44
standby right now before I convince you
otherwise
with multiple view re multiple review
criteria. While the comprehensive plan
anticipated residential development in
this area, actual development plans
patterns, infrastructure constraints,
and market realities have materially
diverged since adoption of the plan. The
comprehensive plan itself recognizes
that amendments are appropriate when
assumptions no longer align with
conditions on the ground. The following
response
will be addressing those items. Number
one, based on beneficial or addresses
unforeseen issues. Benefit to the
community. Staff correctly describes the
Misuse employment category as supporting
business campuses style development
similar to North Range, Swan Ranch, High
Plains Business Park. These areas
provide employment opportunities, tax
base expansions, compatibility with
major transportation, and reduce
conflicts with residential
neighborhoods.
Unforeseen issues. While staff notes
that transportation barriers and lack of
water manes existed in 2014, the plan
could not foresee how persistent and
constraining those conditions would
remain more than a decade later since
adoption. No residential subdivisions
have materialized in this subject area.
Market activity has favored storage,
warehousing, and industrial uses
along with utility providers that major
utility relocations will not occur
substantially limiting the residential
feasibility. Infrastructure improvements
remain speculative and many years out.
The comprehensive plan encourages
monitoring development trends and
responding when assumptions prove
inaccurate. That threshold has been met
here. Our conclusion is proposal does
address unforeseen persistence of
infrastructure constraints and market
non-response and therefore complies with
criteria number one. On number two,
compatibility with the surrounding area
and plan policies. Staff correctly
identified that the subject property is
bounded by LI zoning to the north, east,
west, and southeast.
I80 and Burlington Northern create
strong physical and functional barriers.
Recent trends are predominantly
industrial or storage related. While
residential zoning exists to the
southwest, and I mean southwest along
South West Drive and further way to the
south, that development is already
buffered by distance, roadway
separations, and existing
non-residential uses. Compatibility does
not require uniformity. It requires
appropriate transitions which can be
addressed at zoning, platting, and site
design stages through buffering,
setbacks, and orientation.
Importantly, the FL the future land use
map goal of mixeduse development west of
Burlington, Northern Santa Fe has not
materialized in practice in this
location despite more than a decade of
opportunity. The proposal is
functionally compatible with existing
land uses and barriers and better
reflects actual development patterns
than the current designation.
Number seven on the criterion was strict
adherence to the plan. Staff
acknowledges the plan encourages
responsiveness to market demand. Recent
land use trends have not have been
non-residentidential.
While the plan may have originally
intended to phase out industrial uses
along Southwest Drive, that outcome has
not occurred and strict adherence now
would require forcing residential
development into an environment
dominated by
industrial zoning and utility
constraints.
Strict adherence under these conditions
would produce an outcome inconsistent
with livability, market feasibility, and
long-term success.
It is our conclusion that criterion 7 is
met because adherence to the plan's
original assumption no longer produces a
reasonable planning outcome.
The last item is number eight, public
welfare and plan consistency.
We respectfully disagree with the
conclusion that approving the amendment
would be detrimental to public welfare.
No specific residential project has been
proposed in over a decade. The plan does
not guarantee housing production simply
by designation. Housing goals must be
balanced with location suitability and
employment. Land near interstate and
rail access is a finite resource.
Concerns about domino effects are
speculative and can be addressed through
future discretionary reviews.
Conversely, maintaining an unworkable
designation risk long-term vacancy or
underutilization
which does not serve the public welfare
Cheyenne policies are mixed as staff
acknowledges where policies conflict.
The commission is empowered to weigh
market evidence, infrastructure
realities, functional compatibility,
utility providers, oops, long-term
economic resilience. Our conclusion is
on balance the propo proposal advances
public welfare by aligning land use with
realistic development outcomes while
preserving opportunities for housing in
more suitable locations.
We respectfully submit that criteria 3
through six are fully met per staff.
Criterion 1, 2, 7, and 8 are met when
evaluated against current conditions
rather than outdated assumptions.
The comprehensive plan explicitly
supports flexibility and responsiveness.
For these reasons, we request the
approval of the future land use map
amendment.
Further noted based on some of the
conversation that has occurred tonight,
our property is already zoned in the
city and it is in the city. So, it is
not vacant outside county parcel coming
in. So, all three parcels are that way.
If we weren't experiencing this
situation with data centers at this
point, staff would be asking us to make
sure that all three parcels align with
current zoning for what we planned on
using.
We are a land developer. We develop
homes all day long as you will get
Harmony Valley coming in here shortly
with you and as you saw Bison Apartments
tonight. We have no vision for this
being residential housing over there
because of the constraints by the
railroad, the interstate and Southwest
Drive.
Are we bringing in a data center? No,
that is not the intent whatsoever.
The situation though is that when you
have one piece which is the strip to the
very north of our land, it is zoned LI.
The next piece is AG and then AR. We are
simply trying to go ahead and do what
our surrounding neighbors have done with
LI and bring it forward to LI and use
that use.
I know next month you have property to
the south coming in for a data center. I
think every property has to be viewed
separately and on its own merits and
concerns. And based on that, I would ask
that you not consider it as a data
center, but more as the LI zoning in
this area that fits the use with the
adjacent properties. And I'm here for
any questions.
I've got a question.
We're talking about opportunities and
and planning ahead based on on the
presence of infrastructure and and the
railroad has been highlighted as as a
source of an opportunity in your
presentation.
Is there a sighting there or anything
that would make that railroad accessible
to this parcel
that I'm not seeing
or is this just the railroad is passing
through? And
>> Mr. chair through you if I may answer
your question. The railroads there so
that should a supplier or a manufacturer
for data centers or just for anything in
particular for buildability as in the
property directly to the north
northwest. I I would point out that you
have CH Arbor, you have Advanced Air,
you have uh many warehouse type
businesses that either are producing or
storing and and sale items. We could see
that as a possibility and the connection
to the railroad does lend that
possibility.
So to rule it out would be in it would
be in appropriate for that area.
So this is a stretch of the railroad
that the railroad would be willing to
serve adjacent
adjacent uses without a sighting. Is
that what you're telling me
>> through you, Mr. Chair? That is a
possibility.
It could become a spur off to the side.
It could not. We could work on that. But
at this point, we can't do anything with
the AG zoning or AR.
So we can't pursue other items until
that resolution comes forward.
>> Any other questions
for the for the applicant from
commission
commissioners on Zoom?
Okay, I think thank you for now. Please
stand by.
Will staff please read the report into
the record.
>> Mr. Chair, Conor White Planning and
Development Department filling in for
Seth Lloyd. So, I'll try to do my best.
The two projects before you again, this
is a future land use map amendment and a
zone change. The zone change is
contingent on that future
uh land use map amendment.
The area we're looking at, it's south of
I80
and east of Southwest Drive.
Currently on the future land use map, it
is mixed use uh residential and then it
is zoned
technically county LI,
city AG, city AR. Um the county LII
portion comes in through looking back at
when that portion was actually annexed.
It was tied to a plat. The plat was
never recorded, which means the zoning
never actually went into effect.
So it was zoned LI in the county though,
so it does have something on it. Um
we've counted it as city LI for the
longest time.
So the applicant is requesting future
land use map amendment for roughly 94
acres of land from mixeduse residential
to mixeduse employment to accommodate a
zone change to LI light industrial
um for the purpose of unspecified
mixeduse employment uses.
Property is shown as mixeduse
residential in the future land use map.
The mixeduse residential category
promotes uh self-supporting
neighborhoods. Uh the primary contain
housing uh range of residential housing
types such as single family, duplex,
patio home, townhouse, apartments,
condos, live work units. Uh would be the
majority of uh the uses within this
mixeduse residential category with that
designation.
And that zone or that future land use
designation does consider the mixeduse
residential uh zone district to be the
most optimal zone. However, various
residential zones um and later intense
commercial zones could also be
appropriate.
Uh the future land use map, this will
run with uh concurrent with the zone
change, but this one's going to be a
little different. this one because all
properties are currently within city
limits. This will actually just go
straight to city council for
introduction next Monday,
which means it will be approved.
Basically, it'll have consideration
prior to the zoning being approved. It
does not need to be approved the same
night. Um, decision on the future land
use can take place ahead of that zone
change because the zone change is
contingent on the future land use. So,
this one works a little different than
the one that we discussed earlier. uh
still goes to county commissioners
tomorrow afternoon uh for comment only,
but then would be introduced at council
uh the same basically night as the zone
change would next Monday and then would
go through its two readings uh have
final decision later this month and then
the zone change would have final
consideration the second Monday in May
through steps view. Um there's a lot of
review on this specific parcel taking a
look at the area. Um
you probably noticed that with staff's
um conclusion there is rationale for
both either approval or denial. Um the
rationale for
approval uh would be that although the
current feature land use map encourages
reszoning
out of the current light uh industrial
zones to allow non-industrial uses, most
of the recent development in the
vicinity has been industrial in nature,
including storage units in newly created
county PUD zoning or PUB zones along
Southwest Drive. uh LI and PUD indust um
both LI and PUD industrials uh zoning
exists within the area proposed to be
modified and on three and on three
sides. Although the LU zone to the
southwest
um or also the LU zone to the southwest
although currently developed with
residential uses would allow for light
industrial uses via conditional use
process in the county.
The rationale for denying uh despite the
LIi zone and industri and industrial
development existing in the area at the
time of the comprehensive plan Cheyenne
designates all the land surrounding uh
surrounded by Lincolnway, the BNSF
railroad, college and I25 with non uh
industrial future land use designations.
Expecting the area to tr transition to
residential and commercial development.
Housing is needed in the Cheyenne region
and taking land away from future
residential development without adding
residential development elsewhere may
further limit opportunities to increase
housing supply. There is also currently
residential development to the south and
southwest that could be negatively
impacted by future industrial
development.
Um
furthermore, uh no specific uses have
been identified for the area. Um but
outside of the application, discussions
occurred regarding development of a
campground or recreational vehicle park.
However, specific development would not
necessarily trigger the land uh use plan
uh because it it can be accommodated via
conditional use in the zone districts
that already exist.
Uh staff recognizes that the increase in
construction activity with numerous
large-scale projects and the need for
employee housing. However, if the end
goal of the applicant is to construct a
campground, a recreational vehicle park,
alternative paths to move forward exist
and there may be unintended consequences
of changing the future land use map and
zoning to accommodate a permissible use.
uh in the present zone districts.
The evaluation of the land use plan
amendment and the related zoning should
be based on all possible alternatives in
the desired zone district supported by
mixeduse employment uh land use
category. Once this property is changed
to mixeduse employment, the entire area
might domino into industrial development
and opportunities for future uh
permanent housing in the area may be
lost. Housing is a defined need to the
community and it would be deter um
detrimental to the public welfare to
take land anticipated for urban
residential development and change it to
non-residential uses.
Again, this area is constrained when it
comes to um its boundaries. You do have
the interstates to the north, the
railroad to the east.
Um again, through staff's review, there
was a lot of balancing and trying to
figure out uh which direction this
should go. Ultimately, uh staff's
recommendation does come to recommending
denial of the future land use map
amendment
uh for this parcel.
And I will have two different slides at
the end just in case planning commission
changes their mind or decides to go and
approve it. There are two slides. uh
staff does recommend denial based on our
review and the criteria
um and based on the housing needs and
the fact that with this parcel, this
could trigger more industrial
development within the area.
And in the end, if this is zoned ally,
it doesn't necessarily mean it's going
to be developed the way the developer is
proposing it. As staff, we still have to
look at the fact that you give it all
zoning, it can develop with any
industrial use.
with the zone change. Um, as staff
reviewed that, again, the zone change
basically heavily um
kind of relies on the future land use
map amendment. So, there are two motions
with that one as well. Um, basically, if
planning commission does recommend
approval of the future land use map
amendment, staff would support the zone
change. Um,
looking through the review criteria, if
the future land use map amendment is
supposed to be mixeduse employment, then
the LI zone does fit mixed use
employment. It is one of the zone
districts that we would expect with that
land use designation.
Um, again with the review, there is LII
zoning to the east uh to the north.
So again with that future land use
designation changing
staff would support the zoning map
amendment to LI
if the future land use map amendment
isn't recommended for approval or
approved I should say and is denied then
staff would recommend denial of that
zone change um due to the land being um
under the future land use map as
mixeduse residential. Again, the M
mixeduse residential zone or mixed use
future land use designation does not
support LI zoning. It supports more of
the mixeduse or commercial or
residential type zone districts
as I noted. Um,
LI zoning if that is approved. Alli
zoning does allow for light industrial
uses. Again, we haven't had any specific
projects submitted for this. So, that's
one of the things that I've had to
review is the LI zone does allow for
data centers. It does allow for
industrial uses. Yes, it does allow for
recreational vehicle park or campground
as a permitted use, but it allows for a
lot of other industrial uses as well.
So, all of those have to be taken into
consideration uh with our review. So
again, if the future land use map is
recommend or is approved um by planning
commission, then staff would recommend
approval of that ally zone. If planning
commission does deny the future land use
map, staff would recommend denial of the
zoning map amendment as well. With that,
I am available for any questions.
Chair, I have a couple of questions for
staff on this one. Uh,
so
there was a note about the lack of water
manes and just on staff's opinion, do
you think that
upsizing those water manes would likely
be easier by an industrial user or a
residential use? I'm just
that was
Mr. sure through you and I I believe
through steps review um we did look at
that and I think that might be part of
the reason for recommending approval is
yes when you have a larger industrial
user they may have more money to be able
to put towards those extensions than say
a residential
it kind of depends though because I mean
if you look at some of these larger kind
of
uh residential developments like Whitney
Ranch and stuff that's a residential
developer they they're having to extend
mains
clear out to where they are for their
residential development as well. But
again, that also hasn't developed as
quickly.
So, I believe that might be one of the
reasons that we had in here for approval
is
an industrial developer could bring in
those mains and then maybe that will
trigger residential development
afterwards. I but again, I don't know.
Um but I believe that was something that
staff did think about. I don't know if
we have exact ways of measuring and
saying yes if it goes industrial yes
it'll be easier for mains over a
residential but I think that is
something we've discussed and looked at
and I believe that is one of the reasons
for recommending approval
again this was a whole kind of balancing
that's why Seth had at the end there's
reasons for approval there's reasons for
denial ultimately staff did go with
recommending denial but wanted to
provide that there could be reasons to
approve. It's trying to balance
everything.
I got two more follow-up questions, I
believe. Uh the next one kind of
piggybacks off that one. And uh we look
at policy 2.5b,
workforce housing. And I kind of assume
that workforce housing is more of the
attainable housing. It's not going to be
your larger
lot. So just with that in mind and the
extension of water manes do you foresee
that this would be attainable housing
I'm just
Mr. Chair through you. So if if this
were to develop the way the developer
has discussed with us to a campground or
RV recreational vehicle park under our
new campground regulations.
Um I would say that's considered
workforce housing. That's people
basically coming and living in their RVs
uh for these larger projects.
I don't know what it's going to cost for
all the main extensions
and how that's going to be impacted with
depending what the development is. Um
so that I mean that fits under that
workforce housing though if that's how
it gets developed. But again, as I
mentioned, that development can can take
place without the future land use map
amendment. Um, and has another process
to go through that conditional use
process.
And chair, my last one for now. Uh, and
this is going to also spur within the
community community housing need. Uh and
we previously saw a future land use map
amendment for probably about a
exponential amount more of land. Those
about 100 to a thousand and just looking
at that and our community housing need I
feel like that would probably build
about this would be about 200 homes on a
point4 acre lot or no I a little off but
I believe the other one would be about
2,000 homes. So, I'm just trying to
tease out how that community housing
need and also when we look at the
surrounding area we have
I personally I would rather live
probably on HappyJack Road than being
bound by two major interstates in their
corridor
the BNSF railroad and then having an
adjacent Mellan pipeline right facility.
So I'm just trying to understand staff's
reasoning why the community housing need
was more applicable in this situation
than in the previous
>> Mr. Chair through you. So I believe with
that um when staff looked at the other
one again it just came to being how far
it is from the actual urban core. Um
that's more on the edge of what we had
as the urban service boundary. this one.
You're still kind of closer. I do
understand
with the discussion of having the
railroad in. You've got I80
right there as well. Um
with the mixeduse residential
designation, it looks at higher density
that urban transition that was approved
uh to go to mixeduse employment out on
the edge. Urban transition would not be
looking at the higher density. So when
you say upwards of 2,000 homes, I don't
think that's what we would be seeing out
on that property. Urban transition would
you'd be looking at the AR residential
zone or maybe the LR zone district. So
you'd be looking at a lot less density
out that far.
The mixeduse residential zone district
here, you could be looking at multif
family. you could be looking at a lot
denser residential development with that
designation.
So, I think that's where it comes down
to you've got yes, you've got a larger
property that we were recommending go to
mixeduse employment.
It wouldn't be as dense a residential
development if we left it as that urban
transition as going from mixeduse
residential
to now mixeduse employment.
um mixeduse residential again, it allows
for that higher density than you would
get in the urban transition.
So that's that's I believe how staff
looked at both of those. Um
that would be my analysis of it. Again,
I'm filling in for Seth, so I don't know
if I'm mentioning everything he would
have liked to mention and how he
specifically reviewed it. Um, but from
the way that I would be looking at it,
that's how we would look at the two is
urban transition, you're going to get a
lot less density than you would with
your mixeduse residential.
I'd like to get some more clarification
on staff's um analysis under review
criteria too. I was a little
the the compatibility
with the surrounding area and the
conclusion that that the proposal does
not comply with that.
I was pretty surprised
at the end of the discussion that the
staff reached the conclusion that it
did.
You know, coming into this,
I was trying to figure out why we why we
had
housing, projected residential housing
adjacent to
our, you know, our tank storage
facilities are, I mean, we I know we
discussed kind of a long-term
transportation trying to figure out how
to connect this area maybe across the
interstage.
But we've recent and I I do know we
recently discussed this area and and
trying to figure out how to get people
and to be able to move around this area
and it was really problematic and how to
get people out and safety in and
and
designating different corridors in the
transportation plan for this area. But
I have a hard time envisioning people
stampeding
to live in an area that's sandwiched
amongst two interstates, a railroad, a
pipeline,
and
light industrial in in in the area
around. I I do know that what we're
really supposed to be working with here
is not so much what is the specific
development proposal
before us, even though that should guide
us, but we're talking about an amendment
to
the comprehensive
to the
to to the future land use map, which is
which is much broader than just the
zoning map. And conceptually,
does this area generally
make more sense to be
in industrial employment type uses or
residential type uses and and and so I
guess I don't understand how what this
amendment would do
is not compatible with the surrounding
uses, freight corridors,
and and and land uses.
I don't understand that. And even with
that one flip at that point, then in my
mind, there's more things that that it
complies with than that it doesn't
comply with.
Can you maybe illuminate the thinking of
how how you reach the the prop proposal
doesn't comply or compat is not
compatible with the surrounding areas
more than what's on the page cuz the
logic didn't flow for me.
Mr. Chairman, this is uh Megan online.
May I comment?
>> Yes, please. Thank you for chiming in. I
I um
I actually see where staff is coming
from on this one because if you look at
a map, it looks very flat and and of
course it looks like it's surrounded by
light industrial, but if you're familiar
with the area, this property is actually
kind of walled off, so to speak, from
those light industrials with the
railroad, um the interstate.
um it creates like a like a section
where it it doesn't quite align.
It doesn't quite look as flat as it does
on the map. So, it does kind of look
like it's sectioned off and more part of
that residential area in my opinion. And
um that's where I would support staff in
their recommendation on this property.
Thank you, Commissioner
Honor. It's good to hear from you.
I guess Mr. Chair, I can try to answer
your question.
>> Yes, please. Um, I believe where Seth
was going with this was kind of actually
along the lines of what Commissioner
Connor was saying that
you do have the railroad, you do have
I80. Uh, those do create hard boundaries
though when it comes to the zone
districts that you have east and north.
Um,
with the area again with it being a
designation of mixeduse residential,
we're not saying the whole thing is
going to be residential. you would
expect commercial to also be developed
in the area. It'd be that mix of both
commercial and residential.
Um
I think the biggest thing that Seth was
looking at also was the the park that's
out there. Mixed residential does um
expect to have kind of that closeness to
those open space areas. The county does
have a park that is being upgraded
um and has been um being worked on. So
that does have the amenity that's out
there.
But I think the biggest thing when he
was looking at compatibility is the
boundaries and what is actually in the
area. Once you basically have those
boundaries there and you don't look past
them, what does that area look like?
Otherwise, I don't know if I have the
best answer for you.
>> I think you I understand where you're
coming from, even though I don't know
that I think of a the railroad so much
as a boundary as
as as an impact.
So
the entire corridor
>> uh chair, sorry, this is Charles Bloom,
plan development director. Could you
rephrase your question one more time and
perhaps I can take a stab at that for
you?
>> And I was asking for more clarification
on on how a staff reached the conclusion
that that the proposed amendment does
not comply with uh Uh okay. Comply with
the review criteria that that uh it be
compatible
uh with the surrounding area and the
goals and policies of the plan.
and and I was not so much focused on on
the the land uses that are on the other
side of these various boundaries, even
though I think they're highly relevant,
but with the existence of
of the pipeline, the railroad, uh the
interstates,
I80
as
well, not just yeah, I 80, but but even
thinking about I25, not far to the west,
not so much as as boundaries and and and
and buffers, but as
active freight corridors and and the
impacts of them on the area and how this
would not comply with or would not be
compatible, the amendment would not be
compatible with those.
I see. Okay.
Apologies for that. I was just double
checking to make sure that um I was on
the same page there um with you and
all right I'm pulling up the step as
Connor had noted
uh this was put together by by Seth. He
had he put this together and he's um
absent today and I was actually out when
this was being um developed. Um but
really what was was looking at with this
whole package was it really was a 50/50.
staff was pretty much split right up and
down the middle. Um so if there's
something that the planning commission
feels is,
you know, it is compatible if you choose
to make that finding um it would be
something we would be satisfied with. So
if if you don't necessarily agree with
what staff uh analysis was here, you all
are welcome to overrule it and make that
recommendation. Um really what it had
come down to here and Connor kind of
touched on that a little bit was there
were uh some
other areas uh surrounding this
development like the open space park
area to the north which was uh owned and
maintained by the county. um that this
would like further isolate that um that
there was some residential in the area
that could be developed and it was just
looking at how it all uh comes together
um with those predescribed boundaries
that are there right now, Interstate 80
and the railroad. Um the applicant did
note uh that there is land to the south
of this which um presently it is believe
is zoned a mixeduse residential right
now um where there have been some
discussions of a potential data center
um at that location. So that could
change the way that this whole
compatibility element looks. But if this
is something that the planning
commission feels is is met, um you're
more than welcome to make that finding
uh to uh move this forward in whatever
way you would like.
>> Okay. Thank you. And is there
>> another topic? Has has there been any
feedback or discussion that that staff
is aware of regarding the neighborhood
to the south and and feedback about a
proposed
dare I say man campground?
Has there been comment that I'm missing
here regarding that or is that just kind
of out in the ether? Mr. Chair, I
believe I've only had one phone call.
Um,
again, at the time, again, we don't know
if it's going to be a work or a RV camp
or campground. So, I did not specify
that to the person that called because
we don't have any formal submitt. I just
told them it they're planning to zone it
to light industrial, which allows for
industrial uses. uh their biggest
concern is like I feel like we see with
a lot of projects traffic in the area.
Um
so that was I don't believe they were in
support of either the zone change or the
future land use map amendment. Um
but that was I think their biggest
concern that I they had mentioned to me
which is stating that it was being
proposed to go to light industrial which
allows for light industrial uses was
traffic.
Any other questions for staff on this?
>> Mr. Chair, this is Megan online. I do
have two comments. I just
I just find it concerning when you look
around Cheyenne, the amount of light
industrial or industrial that we shove
right on top of residential
areas. It's it's actually unbelievable
to me. I've not seen it anywhere else.
I would hate to continue to further
that. and two, unspecified use is
concerning um just in just in general
because I believe in in transparency.
And so if there was um a conditional use
or something they wanted to do that fit
light industrial but could also fit
conditionally under what they have, I
would prefer to have us approve a
conditional use on the property.
Thank you.
Any
other questions for staff?
Um, I'll open this up for public
comment. Is there any member of the
public that's here that wants to comment
on this propos on I guess on either of
these? We're mostly seem to be
discussing the land use map amendment.
And I should note for any public that's
online, please use the raise hand
feature.
>> Yes, please do that.
Is there any member of the public
online? Okay, with that, I'm going to
Okay.
Okay. I I I struggle with finding my
hand raising feature sometimes. Okay. So
with that, I'm going to close public
comment.
Um,
does applicant want to address any of
the questions that are out there?
You would applicant would like to
Mr. Chair through you John Sers true
grit agent. So in regards to the water
manes, the water man is actually sitting
on the north side of Interstate 80. It
would have to be brought across
sewer is across the street. That's it.
There is nothing else over there. Um,
you do have WA running diagonally across
the property. I think Mr. Hibbons could
probably prove that as he was out there
today. We also have a north south line
and we have two diagonal gas lines
running through this area. So
as to creating residential housing,
we honestly being in the land
development business, this has not been
as owning this see this as that
situation. Currently we have uh Bison
Brand Landscaping with their nursery out
there. We believe that that site will
continue to operate at this point. Um we
have been in touch with uh Jeannie Groen
who's on the front side of that and she
had no concerns. I did receive a co
phone call from Nate Davidson just
asking what we are doing today and we'd
keep him advised in regards to
attainable housing. I need to point this
out because Mr. Olsson brought up
something. So, for what it's worth, we
ran at Cox to be honest with you and no,
it wasn't urban housing. It was um this
need in this community for uh what's
happening. Um, as you will see next
month, uh, we have Harmony Valley 23rd
filing coming before this body. Uh, that
will bring in another 196, uh, single
family residential lots to add to the
112 that we already have, which will be
308.
We don't expect that to last three
years,
if two.
So, when we say we are looking for land,
we are looking for land. We understand
that you have data centers coming in
here spending big bucks on big pieces of
parcel of land and it makes it very much
unattainable for residential home
builders and developers to pay that
price and get affordable attainable
housing. So we did look at at that Cox
Ranch specifically for that because
there is a concern that once all this
happens and the housing how many more
apartment complexes do we really want
that are huge? um are they really
long-term residents or are they people
that are actually buying houses and
living and staying? So, we get it. If if
anybody gets it in the affordable
housing market, we're we're raising our
hands. With that said, being an
affordable housing builder, this is not
an area we see as residential. I wanted
to point out that property at Long
College is owned by a lady that lives in
um Colorado. She has 22.14 acres in the
property. I believe it's Mountain Shadow
subdivision or so.
Those lots have been there forever. No
sales, no movement. What you see when
you drive out there is you see
residences that have three or four lots
combined. They have a house, they have a
shop, they they don't want any other
rules. You also sit back and if you look
at that subdivision, the rightway widths
are 40 feet. That's it. It doesn't even
meet the city standards.
I will say Mr. Bloom misqued the
property directly south of us is MUB
already. It is not mixed use or
residential. So there is that in play at
this moment that that is mixeduse
business. So if somebody was to try to
make residential, they would have to go
ahead and try to figure that out.
Chairman, are you okay?
Okay. Um I get the idea that of
transparency. I also understand at this
exact moment we potentially have three
different clients looking at this
potential land. One is for an RV
campground and I want to be specifically
clear, an RV campground is not a work
camp. I have gotten hammered on that
already on another property and hence
the reason why you have an RB campground
in the in the set of the UDC guidelines
at this point and staff can clearly tell
you that one. Um that is one option.
There is options for manufacturing
or data centers andor other uses just
for storage just to help out the
community with the need for places for
manufacturing and so forth. We're
running out of those as well. They don't
want to go out to Swan and pay for the
big piece of land. There is the option
of smaller. The railroad is a
consideration significantly based on
product availability and what you can
get into the community. So I can't fully
say that at this moment we are 100% this
that or the other. But based on the
three zonings of our property and the
surrounding use that is all LI
regardless of whether or not a railroad
or a roadway exists. It does exist that
the LI is touching at our property lines
at that point.
Be happy to answer any other questions.
I think we've closed public comment and
gave you a chance to respond to
questions.
With that, I believe
I'm looking for a motion from the
commission
>> and commission. I should specify
tell me which slide because this one was
>> not easy to fit on both on one. So,
>> okay. Well, let's let's find out who who
wants to offer a motion and they can
tell us.
>> Mr. Chair, I would uh I would I'm going
to support the land use change, so I
would prefer to make the approved
motion.
>> Okay. Commissioner Leair,
>> I move to approve the resolution
amending the future land use plan for a
portion of land south of I80 and east of
Southwest Drive as shown in the exhibit
A from mixeduse residential to mixeduse
employment.
>> Do I have Okay, it's been moved by
Commissioner Lair and seconded by
Commissioner Hibben.
Is there is there any discussion of the
motion
by the commission?
Is there any discussion by commissioners
who are on Zoom?
>> I think Mr. Chairman, I've made my
stance pretty clear on this one, so you
can expect that my vote will go in that
direction.
>> Okay. Thank you, Commissioner Connor.
Um, any other comment,
desire to amend?
Seeing none, will staff please call roll
for and my understanding is this is uh
for uh item I item I.
>> Yes, Mr. Chair, we are on item I. So, we
are on the future land use map
amendment.
Lonnie Olsson.
>> Hi.
>> Megan Connor.
>> No.
>> Amy Hernandez.
>> Nay.
>> Is that a That was a no.
>> Correct.
>> Daryl Hibbons.
>> Yes.
>> Tony Lair.
>> I.
>> Mr. Chair. I believe that motion passes.
because I believe it's affirmative of
those present.
So I don't know if the chair
>> there's six members and we've got Yeah,
it's three to two.
>> I I never have it though.
>> Correct. So I I would say that motion
passes
>> there for you. I do believe that it has
to be a majority of the uh planning
commission has to vote on this
amendment. We just should probably check
the bylaws really quick if we can. With
that being the case, I believe the chair
would need to vote. I'll double check.
>> I am also going to pull that up. I just
want to make sure just in case we're on
session
of how close
and chair of the commission, I do
believe that it may also be outlined in
state statute under uh master plan
section that is the majority of the
commission um to approve a land use plan
change.
>> Okay, let me look that up then.
here within our bylaws chapter 6 section
two it states official business to
transact official business a quorum must
be present majority of those present in
voting may approve or disapprove
official business
the chair shall not vote as a member of
the planning commission unless a tie
vote occurs of the majority present and
voting I think I believe with present
that would signify those attending and
not the seven members of the commission
but I could be wrong as I am not an
attorney unlike you. I would agree that
it is those present.
Chair, members of the commission, um I
have found the relevant state statute.
It is Wyoming state statute 151-505,
master plan, manner of adopting
generally certification thereof. It says
the commission may adopt the master
plan, which is also the land use plan in
parts. um as the plan progresses or as a
whole. Any part of the plan shall
correspond generally with one or more of
the functional subdivisions of the
subject matter thereof. The adoption of
the plan or any plan part amendment or
addition shall be by resolution carried
carried by the affirmative vote of not
less than a majority of the commission.
Uh the resolution shall refer expression
to maps da da da da. So it is the
affirmative vote of the um commission.
Uh Seth and I had identified this um
issue when it came to uh the bylaws and
state statutes that they don't quite
marry up on that. What Commissioner
Olsen did note is true. That does say
that the uh chair um is able to or shall
vote in the event of a tie. I think it
would likely
I would think that it could be
considered
um that he could vote in this case if he
wanted to
uh move forward with this with a yes
vote.
I hope that provides a little bit of
clarification here.
I think the question is is do I need to
vote given that the
given that the majority of the
commission has voted?
>> Sure.
>> To the extent that I need to vote. Uh
yes, Charles,
>> I I don't believe you would need to
vote. Um if you did not vote, our
message to the governing body would be
that um you all had a majority vote uh
to um approve which passed but um it was
not officially adopted by the planning
commission because it lacked the
majority of the membership and they in
their turn would have the ability to um
adopt it with modifications or just
adopt it in general
>> because I'm not convinced that I get to
plan and that I get to vote in the
absence of a tie.
>> Chair, that is fair. That's a fair
evaluation of the situation.
I think I think in the absence of a tie,
I don't get to vote. Even if I want to
vote, I don't think I get to.
I think that's fair. And we'll relay
this in our memorandum to the governing
body so they're aware of what had
transpired and why a 3-2 vote is not a
vote to approve.
Okay, with that
>> point of order, Mr. Chair.
>> So, okay. So, again, we we talked
briefly about the process and this
so-called resolution and that this
planning commission is is it one of the
approving people on the or entities for
the resolution? Can this can the
governing body go ahead and approve the
resolution even though we both didn't?
>> Mr. Chair, yes. So, the governing body
can basically overrule planning
commission and still approve the future
land use map amendment.
>> Okay. because I was thinking I mean if
there if there's a big gray area here we
could just we could postpone this
um action for another month and do some
additional research on what exactly we
need to have to go forward
now I'm looking that
So I I I guess probably the the first
step is is can can staff please report
the result of the roll call vote.
>> Mr. chair. So due to a 3 to2
vote not having a majority of those on
planning commission vote in favor of the
recommended motion to approve that
motion does fail.
Okay. And with that, I do think that we
I I need to call for
a motion on item J.
Commissioner Connor, would you like to
offer the motion on item J?
U Mr. Chairman, I'm on my phone. I don't
have the screen in front of me.
You're being told, right?
Do I have a motion on item J?
>> Chair,
>> Commissioner Olsen. Uh, I move to
recommend the governing body deny the
resoning of tract one H andB tracks
and lot two block one H andB tracks
second filing to LA
White Industrial as shown in the
attached zone change map noting the
project does not meet review criteria
one two um and eight the LA zoning
request being incompatible with the
future land use designation of mixeduse
residential.
I second.
>> I've got a motion and a second.
>> Chair, uh, I just want to state for the
record, I am moving to deny this due to
the future land use map not passing and
that being staff's recommendation and
seeing it incompatible. I was in favor
of the future land use map being
changed, but due to us having to go with
our review criterion, I am voting to
support the denial.
Okay. Any other further comment from
other members of the commission?
Debate, discussion
hearing? None. Will staff please call a
roll.
>> Tony Lair.
>> Hi.
>> Daryl Hibbons.
>> Lonnie Olsson.
>> Hi.
Megan Connor,
>> no.
>> Megan, just for clarification, this is a
recommendation of denial for the zone
change. So, vote yes would be in favor
of that motion.
>> Oh. Um, thank you for clarifying, Conor.
I'd like to change my vote to I.
>> Amy Hernandez,
>> I.
>> Mr. Chair, that motion passes.
>> Thank you.
other business staff chair. Could I have
a brief moment uh if your
>> commission allows that in deal?
>> Yes.
>> Uh so I probably you guys might have
seen that there's a open vacancy for the
planning commission and I just want to
note that that is me. Uh if we do have a
midmon meeting that will be my last one.
uh I'm retaining my current job in the
city of Cheyenne, but I will be residing
outside of Cheyenne and the county and
thus with I don't feel ethically it's
right to serve on a board where I don't
live in the community and also per abide
laws I can't. So with that, I just
wanted to say thank you to everyone on
the board and staff. It's been an honor
serving up here with you all and I hope
for the best moving forward. Thank you
for your service.
Any
other business staff announcements?
>> Unless Charles corrects me if I'm wrong,
we don't have a midmon planning
commission meeting. So, this is Lonnie's
last meeting.
>> Thank you.
>> Honor is correct.
>> So, there will be no midmon. Um, our
next meeting will be May 4th. Uh that
agenda is starting to grow kind of large
as well. So be prepared for
possibly another long meeting. Um can
say there's probably a couple future
land use map amendments, some more zone
changes.
Uh plat city initiated zone change will
be on that agenda as well uh for
business park zoning for one of our
business parks.
Um that's just more of a cleanup.
They're already hi in LA, we're just
making them BP.
Um,
as long as I don't get stuck with a lot
of other things that should be coming to
May. Um,
other than that, I don't think I have
any any other announcements besides uh
what I mentioned earlier. I believe
right now the RFP for the update to plan
Cheyenne is currently in our um
it's with TJ. So it's with our
purchasing manager.
>> Yeah, Charles was going to correct me.
It's with our purchasing manager
um to get that process rolling. So that
should hopefully be out shortly um so we
can start getting that moving.
>> Yeah. Thank you.
Anything else,
>> chair?
>> I have no fur further updates.
>> Thank you, sir. With that, I believe
we're adjourned.